Heat. Hey. Hey. Hey.
[music]
Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to this
extraordinary episode of Ask Vijit
episode 336 extraordinary because it is
an unscheduled one. We usually do it on
weekends but we have the Iran war
situation going on and we need to keep
an eye on that and that's why I am doing
this one. So uh yeah we're going to
mainly discuss the Iran war but I'll
also take questions about any other
topics that you have but I hope it's
mainly about the situation because it is
turning into a global crisis. It's
turning into a genuine global crisis. A
lot of pressure is on India right now
and we'll discuss that also why there is
a lot of pressure on India right now and
increasing pressure on India. So before
we get into all these things let's see
what is there on the live stream. I can
see toxic sirishti siriguri kapalin 13
um aditaumar ram iit it's neil akshi
bhardage panduranga07 kennel 4605
nabitadas hello koko tyrion from the UK
hello J7 namaste meet mystery Apurva
aurva anupa amrit singh abishek shukla
live and holy kishukam night everybody
Wish you all a very happy, holy uh Shri
Raachandra.
Alka Shikari, Alka Shikari. Namaste.
Trupti. Hello. Manhattan. I6W. Somi is
here from Jaipur. Real painter. Shalom.
Omar. Hello. Uchiha. Kanishkarhana.
Shashank Koshik. Good evening. Ryan J6.
Heisenberg. Hello. Aka Bardage S.
Morgan.
Trace K's mindset
Mr. Rohit Raj tapa kamill prashar from
merit up anuman bahhuguna mit raj mit
raj singh chadasama proper jellyfish
random skull js j krishna uh shas jadav
shashank koshik uh udas udas
cisodia
atma atma deepa crazy brain good evening
it's Neil Heisenberg hyphen and so many
other people so many other people who
else we have anul Dur Dashan
Dur Dashan. Uh Romesh Jodi Namaste.
Kaneshk also Aman George ready always
ready an Anan Gore unbelievable to be
able Priyanku Poli Sumit Agarwal
Manhattan Soldier Boy Advatini Arya
Rudra Avatar uh Adita once again ETL
Masters History Go Teen Talk 1727 it's
Neil Sunx Brianu Swastik Koh and
everyone else all right thank you so
much for being on the live stream as
always thank you very
Uh so yeah, Iran the Iran war is going
on. The entire matter is escalating.
It's going beyond just the Gulf region.
Now the straight of hormones is still
closed and it's creating a global
crisis, a global shock, not just oil,
but even other things as well. And
there's escalation in our own backyard
now. There's escalation in India's own
backyard.
And the way things are going, many other
nations could get involved over time.
And if other nations get involved, if
European nations get involved, if Russia
gets involved, if China gets involved,
if India is dragged into this matter,
this is no longer a regional conflict.
It's a world war.
Yeah. So Trump, Donald Trump has dragged
us into the situation. It's becoming a
global crisis. So what has happened thus
far? It's been 4 days of the war. The
war has been going on for 4 days. The
war began on a weekend. Trump thought
that it will be over in a weekend's
time, but clearly not the case, right?
Clearly, that's not what happened. It's
still going on. And Iran is
demonstrating
surprising resilience. And Iran is
demonstrating that it can hit back at
everybody. It's targeted how many
countries so far? Obviously, Israel has
been targeted. uh the US assets have all
been targeted in all the Gulf Gulf
nations. So it's like seven, eight, nine
nations that have been targeted targeted
by Iran thus far, mainly Israel and also
some of the other Gulf all the other
other Gulf countries where the US has
assets, military bases and so on. And it
looks like the damage that Iran is
causing is significant.
Now if you look at Twitter X they are no
longer allowing uploads of uh you know
more recent events videos especially
Israel apparently has put a imposed a
blackout on videos so videos can't come
out of Israel of what's happening
because it looks like Iran is turning
Tel Aiv into Gaza. Iran is is you know
doing very heavy missile strikes on on
all these Israeli assets, Israeli
cities. Iran looks like it has uh done
significant damage to the US fifth fleet
headquarters in Bahrain
and so much more. So let's quickly go
through I've got these notes here and
let's quickly go through as as to what's
happened. So as as of today morning is
Israel has launched 10 waves of air
strikes on theran. So the Israelis are
going after the Iran. They are hitting
Thran mainly. You know, you know what's
interesting?
Before this war began,
there was clearly
a certain amount
of dissatisfaction
against the Iranian regime among the
people of Iran. There were some parts of
Iran where a lot of people did not did
not support the regime. they wanted the
region to go and this sentiment was
mainly concentrated in the large cities
of Iran because that's where you have
the educated people the English speaking
people and so on and many of those
people wanted this government to be
overthrown the regime of the ayatlas and
mulas so many of these people in the big
cities wanted the regime to be
overthrown many of these people wanted
America to do a regime change and what
is the US and Israel what are they doing
they are bombarding those cities is
they are bombarding the cities where you
have pro- US sentiment
and they are doing heavy bombardment. 10
waves of air strikes thus far by Israel
itself by Israel alone. Yeah.
And then Iran Israel goes and uh and and
does an air strike on on a school in
Iranian school. It causes the deaths of
I don't know more than 150 children,
girls.
Do you think that sentiment that pro-
US- sentiment and anti- Iran government
sentiment will continue if US and Israel
continues to do that?
So wherever you have the sentiment that
that wherever you had this sentiment
that was pro- US anti-Iran those places
have been bombed and the regions in Iran
where you have a pro regime sentiment
that's the small towns and rural areas
nothing has happened there
and obviously
the the US and Israel went ahead and
assassinated the Ayatah the supreme
leader of not just Iran but the entire
Shia community in the
And this happened during the the Islamic
sacred month of Ramadan.
So it's like going back to the early
days of the Shia Shia faith, right? When
Imam Hussein was martyed at Karbala.
That's the kind of thing that that the
Americans have done. So it was a
fantastic tactical victory for the
Americans. They took out they
decapitated the leadership. They took
out the Ayatah.
But it's a strategic disaster because it
has unified the country.
The Shia faith is all it's it's all
based on on martyrdom on sacrifice and
they have evoked precisely those
sentiments that that's unified not just
the nation of Iran but all the Shia
people in the world and even the Sunni
people are coming in support.
It's a strategic disaster.
Okay. Because now Iran can say that the
Americans are the zalim, the oppressors.
Zaleim and we Iran, we are the masloom.
We are the oppressed. Oppressor
oppressed.
I mean, what are they doing?
And then Israel has the Iran has this
massive stockpile of maybe 100,000 plus
drones, Shahed drones, and maybe I don't
know how many thousands of ballistic
missiles. There are all kinds of numbers
floating around, maybe 3,000, maybe
10,000, somewhere in that range. So Iran
can afford to keep going on and on.
And the Americans have the Patriot
missile defense system, Patriot
interceptor missiles. Those are running
out. Israel has iron dome. Those
interceptor missiles are running out.
How will they replace those? And the
Americans, they they used up about 20%
of their global stockpile of Tomahawk
missiles in the first day of strikes.
And now Iran is is is hitting at
American facilities, American radars,
extremely expensive radars, billion
dollar radars of which there are only a
handful in the world.
The Americans are now contemplating
bringing in the terminal high altitude
area defense system THAD from South
Korea.
If you pull it out of South Korea and
bring it here to the Gulf, then who's
going to defend South Korea? Isn't it
fantastic for China if this happens?
The Americans are making big blunders.
Looks like there were Looks like Trump
was expecting it'll be over in a
weekend. This is not getting over in any
weekend. It's not getting over in a
couple of weeks. It's not going to get
over in a couple of months.
The
Trump has walked into a trap of his own
making. Maybe not his own making.
Maybe it's Netanyahu who dragged him
into the trap because Marco Rubio, the
US foreign secretary a couple of days
ago said in his interaction with the US
media that the US knew that if somebody
attacked Iran then Iran will attack the
US and we knew that somebody was going
to attack Iran. What was that? It was
obviously Israel. So because Israel was
going to attack Iran and then Iran would
have attacked us. That's why we also
attacked Iran first because we knew that
Israel can't be stopped. So essentially
he admitted that Israel can force the US
into a war with Iran.
Right? So that's where the situation is.
The US is running out of options. Israel
has a big Iran has a huge stockpile of
drones and and ballistic missiles. It
can afford to go on for months.
And Iran has activated a mosaic defense
strategy. So even if the Americans take
out all their leaders, kill all the
leaders, complete decapitation, even
then Iran will keep fighting. How will
they keep fighting? Iran has created
this has activated mosaic defense which
means that there are see in Iran there
are 31 states, 31 provinces. Each
province will is going to have its own
army and each army will act
independently. They will have their own
drones, their own missiles, their own
stockpiles of oil and all that arms,
ammunition, everything and their own
command and control structure. And even
the command and control structure will
have its designated survivors. So if the
top guy is taken out, the next guy comes
in. If he's taken out, the next guy
comes in. So the entire structure is
going to remain intact no matter what
happens. So even if they run out of
drones, even if they run out of
missiles, they will fight with small
arms. If they artillery, what that what
not? If they run out of artillery shells
and all, they will fight with small
arms. If they run out of small arms,
they'll find fight hand to hand. They
will not give up.
And each army is independent. This is
going to be this is going to last months
if it if it goes on the way it's going
on right now. It's going to it's going
to last months. The Americans have
walked into a trap with their eyes open.
Right? That's the situation right now.
So, let's see. Let me just go through
what's happened. The Israelis have
launched 10 waves of air strikes on
Thran as of Wednesday morning. Americans
are claiming 2,000 targets have been
struck, 2,000 munitions used in the
first 100 hours and so on. So, Israel is
targeting Thran and Western Iran and the
US is targeting drone bases and southern
Iran infrastructure. Israel is targeting
government institutions of Iran, police
headquarters, intelligence facilities,
IRGC bases, all that. Uh, Israel claims
its F-16s are flying operating over
Thran. They have achieved air
superiority. That's what they're
claiming. Um, that sort of thing. Iran
seems to have fired at least 500
ballistic missiles uh and more than
2,000 drones since the first day of the
war. And Iran has deliberately used old
stock old missiles, cheap missiles and
cheap drones
as dr as decoys to drain the stock
piles, the interceptor stock piles of
the US and Israel. So the old stock, the
20 year old missiles, that's that's the
missiles they're using right now.
sacrificial missiles to to you know to
to drain the interceptor stocks of the
US and Israel and now Iran may be
shifting it's maybe moving to more
sophisticated and more modern ballistic
missiles and we have seen the use of
some of those and that is pretty
frightening those missiles are very
capable they they're able to fragment
into multiple decoys and whatnot and
they're hypersonic like Mark 11 mark 12
that sort of thing um and the rate at
which Iran is launching missiles is
declining about 350 on day one, 50 on
day 50 on day four. So they are, you
know, slowing down the the the they're
reducing the number of missiles they're
launching per day and maybe it's a
strategic move that they are doing that.
U 17 Iranian warships have have
apparently been destroyed. That's what
the Americans are claiming. And today a
very
very uh you could say escalatory
incident happened in the Indian Ocean.
So there was this Iranian warship okay
that was operating that had participated
in a naval exercise in India
and it was it had left India. It was
somewhere in the vicinity of Sri Lanka
and that Iranian warship was torpedoed
torpedoed. Okay. Uh by
it was torpedoed by uh by an American
submarine.
Let me try and find that
the Americans have officially
agreed, you know, claimed this the
skill.
Okay, let's let's take a look at this.
So the American Secretary of War Pete
Hegth says in the Indian Ocean an
American submarine sunk an Iranian
warship that thought that it was safe in
international waters. It was sunk by a
torpedo quiet death
and this happened in
essentially India's zone of interest in
the Indian Ocean in the Sri Lanka region
which is India's region of interest and
that that ship was coming from India.
So is this an attempt to drag India into
the war? Yeah. And the Iranians have
have destroyed a lot of American
infrastructure, naval infrastructure in
the Gulf region, which means that
American warships may not be able to
dock in those ports. Then the question
is where do the American warships dock
in the region? Do they go all the way to
Diego Garcia, south of the Maldives?
That's too far. It'll take 4 days to go
and 4 days to return like more than 7
days. makes no sense. So where will the
American warships dock? You know what's
interesting? India and the US have
signed an agreement called Lemoa
which kind of gives us the US Navy
access to Indian ports.
So is the Indian government going to be
forced by the Americans to give American
warships access to Indian ports for
supply for resupplying for for whatever.
If that happens, India becomes a direct
party in the war against Iran.
You know these agreements Kasa, Lemoa,
all that stuff we have signed with the
Americans for interoperability and so
on.
So the pressure is now going to be on
India very heavily from the Americans
because their bases in the region have
been severely damaged and the Iranians
can hit those bases those those naval
facilities and so on at will with their
ballistic missiles and drones
right so this limo kasa etc it may not
be mandatory
but hey we have signed it even if it's
not mandatory if somebody comes and
twists your arm all the way it may
become mandatory. Do you understand
that? On paper, it may not be mandatory.
In the real world, there are other rules
that that apply.
Um, so what else has happened? 17
Iranian warships have been destroyed.
Apparently, that's what the Americans
claim. The Americans claim they have
lost six soldiers thus far. I think the
actual number may be 100 times more.
Okay. Uh, Iran has downed about 10% of
America's MQ9 Reaper fleet. It shot down
at least three F-15s.
Okay. Uh, what else do we have? What
else do we have? The Iranians have
destroyed an um
an early warning an early warning radar
at Aluda air base in Qatar. That radar
alone costs $1.1 billion. Only six
radars have been built in the world and
one is gone. It is irreplaceable.
And that war that radar gives the
Americans early warnings of what's
coming towards them. Now they don't have
that. They're blind. they will have late
warnings now not early warnings. It was
the backbone of all the American missile
defense in the entire Gulf region and it
was giving data to all the Patriot
systems, all the THR systems, all the
EGUS systems that that that protect
aircraft carriers.
So that radar is blind now. It's gone.
And the Americans have two aircraft
carrier strike groups deployed in this
region. One is in the eastern
Mediterranean off the coast of Israel.
The other one was near Hormuz.
And what where is that aircraft carrier
now? It's gone further south into the
Arabian Sea into the Indian Ocean. Far
from Hormos. Why? Because the Iranians
can take it out. So I on this channel
have been saying for years that India
should not invest in aircraft carriers.
Aircraft carriers are sitting ducks. And
people have been making fun of me for
years now. Look at what the Americans
are doing. They're trying to hide their
aircraft carrier. Aircraft carriers are
sitting ducks in a in a modern war. This
should hopefully
open your eyes about the utility or not
or not aircraft carriers not being
useful. Even the Americans can't
guarantee the safety of their aircraft
carriers,
right? Uh so what else has happened?
Qatar has claimed that a lot of missiles
and drones have been fired at Aludai air
base. Okay. And one of those has hit the
radar, the American radar, $1.1 billion
radar. So that sort of thing. Um, US
radar and sat satellite communication
infrastructure have been has been
targeted across five countries, Bahin,
Qatar, Kuwait, Saudi Arabia and the UAE.
Uh, US interceptor systems in the Gulf
are partially blind now. They don't have
advanced warning of what's happened of
what's happening in real time. Uh, the
US weapon stockpile is being depleted in
real time. Um, 5 years of US Tomahawk
cruise missile supply was was used up in
just 3 days. more than 400 Tomahawk
missiles. Okay. Uh so the first two days
alone consumed 20% of the US global
stockpile of tomahawk missiles and now
Trump is panicking. The Pentagon is
preparing an $50 billion emergency uh
request to to manufacture more system
more munitions and arapon systems and
whatnot. Right. Um Trump is meeting with
Loheed Martin and asking them to
accelerate production of whatever
they're making. Um right so the Iranians
ship that was destroyed by the Americans
by their submarine at least 100 sailors
are missing. Sri Lanka has been able to
rescue about 30 of them and uh Iran has
retaliated by striking a US destroyer
near Indian waters
on the west coast of India. Now what are
these US destroyers doing near Indian
waters? Are we already giving them
access to our ports? That is not known
to me. But there is a possibility.
The big question is, is India already
allowing US warships and naval assets to
use Indian waters in Indian ports? If we
are doing that, we are directly involved
in the war against Iran. If we are doing
that, you see India is now this is no
longer a foreign war. Now
this is already in our backyard anyway.
The Gulf region is like 2 hours from the
west coast of India by flight. But now a
US warship has been hit by the Iranians
possibly in Indian waters or near Indian
waters of the west co west west coast of
India and that raises the question of is
India already giving access to to the
ports of I don't know Mumbai Goa
whatever it is west coast to the
American warships if that is the case
are we really a sovereign nation or
maybe we are because we have signed limo
kasa or whatever
uh straight of hormuz is what is causing
this global crisis it is closed Now it
is effectively closed. 20% of the global
oil supply is dep is disrupted
completely.
40 50% of India's oil supply is
disrupted. Now what do we do about it?
Russia says they they will give us the
oil.
So India will have to turn to Russia
again. We had almost stopped I suppose
allegedly buying oil from Russia and now
we will say okay Russia please send us
oil again.
But will it be enough for for our oil
requirements? India allegedly has I mean
according to reports which are by
official sources ANI and whatnot.
According to multiple reports, India
only has 25 days of oil left.
India's strategic oil reserves are 25
days. China has like one year or
something. India has 25 days. Was the
government of India sleeping? Did they
not anticipate that this war could
happen?
Right.
So, we'll have to buy oil from Russia.
Maybe we'll have to purchase oil from
the US.
Yeah.
Um, that's not the only thing about
hormones. Okay.
So,
um,
Roy mustang speak responsibly. Your
opinion can trickle down and become the
voice of Indian Twitter. India
supporting US war effort narrative is
bad for us. I am simply stating what's
happening. I am speaking very
responsibly. Thank you very much.
I am speaking about what is happening
right now. Go and look at the reports.
I'm not inventing stories here. Right?
Support India supporting US war effort
there. It is bad for us. But if it is a
fact and should I lie to you?
If it is actually happening, then what
should I say? It's not happening. Should
I lie?
I don't know what you're trying to say.
Anyway, what was I saying? Yeah,
hormones, right? Straight of hormones.
So, it's closed
about 40 50% of India's oil imports are
affected by that and it's going to
remain affected because the Americans
can't open the state of Hormos. Why
[snorts] do I say that the Americans
can't open the state of Hormos? Let's
say the Americans sends warship. The
Americans send warships to the state of
Hormos. What happens?
Can they open it? The Iranians can take
down those goddamn warships with their
missiles.
It is a numerical certainty,
mathematical certainty that if you have
enough ballistic missiles coming down,
it at least a few of them will hit. The
Iranians can make ruins out of the
American naval force in the region. Let
me give you an example. Okay, let's open
the map. Let me tell you, let me give
you a a very pertinent example here. Why
I say that they can't open the straight
of Hormos even by force. Look here. This
is the straight of Hormos here. This one
here, this is the straight that is
closed.
Okay?
Now, there is another straight here
called Babal Mandib. The straight of
Babal Mandib. For the past two two and a
half years, the Houthis of Yemen have
blockaded the straight of Bab al-
Mandib. The Houthis are a small ragtag
government. They are a very backward
nation.
Okay, they are a nation that is almost
destroyed and in ruins and Iran supplies
them with some drones and and some
missiles. Using those poultry supplies
of drones and missiles, the Houthis have
located the street of Babal Mandep for
the past 2 years. more than two years
and the Americans have launched hundreds
of air strikes on the Houthis and they
have failed to defeat the Houthis and
they have failed to force the Houthi to
open the street of Babal Mandeb.
Eventually the Houthis agreed that they
will allow American ships to transit but
they said Israeli ships can't transit
and because the Houthis are insisting
Israeli ships can't transit. That's why
Israelis can't use the spread. So even
after two and a half years of bombarding
Yemen, the Americans have failed to open
the straight of Babal band despite their
naval might and air force superiority.
So if they can't force the Houthis to
open that straight, do you think the
Americans can force the Iranians to open
the straight of Hormuz? Impossible. It's
not going to happen. So the strait is
going to be closed for the foreseeable
future.
That's going to give you an oil price
shock in the world. Oil prices are going
to shoot up
and India will have to look for
alternatives.
Definitely Russia and then Trump imposes
25% sanctions on us again, tariffs on us
again. Fine, so be it. And we may also
have to buy oil from Russia, from the
US. In that case, they will insist stop
buying Russian oil. So India is now in a
difficult position.
When it comes to the Gulf countries,
Saudi Arabia,
UAE, Qatar, Oman, etc., etc., etc., all
these Gulf nations, Kuwait, Bahrain,
these nations are artificial nations
built on sand.
They don't produce any agriculture,
next to nothing. So, how do the how do
they have such big populations?
They have big populations because they
import
the majority of their food stuffs. Go to
a market. Go to a mall in Dubai or
wherever. You will see all kinds of food
stuffs there. Fresh. They come from
India. They come from South America.
They come from wherever in the world.
Where do these food stuffs come from?
They come from the through the straight
of Hormuz. The other direction. Now that
the straight of hormos is closed, these
nations are very rapidly going to face a
food crisis.
H. And about 35% of the global
fertilizer supply also comes from
hormones. If that is stopped the whole
world will face a food crisis.
Do you understand? This is a global
crisis we are facing just because of
this closure of this one straight of the
state of Hormos right. Um and oil so the
UAE is a major oil producer and they
have a port called Fujira. Where is
Fujira? Let's go.
So if you look at the state of Hermuz
the straight the port of Fujira. Okay,
where is Fujira? One second. Uh, zoom
out. Zoom out. Fujira. Here it is. The
port of Fujira belongs to the UAE and
it's on the eastern side of the straight
of Hormos which means it is it cannot be
blockaded. So what's happened now is
that the Iran the Iranians have taken
out this port. They've they've hit uh
this port of Fujira and that's why even
this port can't be used for exporting
oil by the UAE.
So the UAE now can't export oil even if
they even if they want to bypass the
trade of foremost because they can't.
Okay. Uh that is the situation. Saudi
Arabia's largest refinery has been
bombed. Iraq's second largest oil field
has been shut down. Pjara Fuja is
attacked. Okay. Even the dalin
desalination plant and power plant of
Fuja has been uh struck and set on fire.
These nations, Gulf nations, these the
desert nations, they depend on de des
desalination plants for water. If you
take these desalination plants offline,
they will have no fresh water to drink.
Then what do they do?
You see how many pressure points are
there? Yeah. Um and the US Navy says it
can't provide escorts to any ships to
transit the straight of because they'll
also be targeted. Um all that is
happening a lot is happening. Israel has
invaded Lebanon. Lebanon in a Lebanon
Hisbollah has fired miss rockets at
Israel. Yeah. Uh Baghdad the
international airport has been shut.
Oman has been hit. Uh the US embassy in
Beirut has been has been shut down. Uh
all that is happening. Yeah. Apparently
the Natan's nuclear site has been hit by
the Americans again. You see last year
there was a 12-day war between Israel
and Iran and at the end of the war Trump
ordered the bombing of Natans and Furo
nuclear power nuclear plants with
stealth bombers and those plants were
bombed and then Trump announced to the
whole world that Iran's nuclear
capabilities have been destroyed
completely.
That's what he announced last year.
Trump that Iran's nuclear capabilities
have been permanently destroyed and now
he is claiming
that we are fighting this war to to make
sure Iran doesn't become a nuclear
power. So was he lying last year or is
he lying today? Because somewhere he has
lied
right. So now they have hit Natans again
and the Busher nuclear power plant also
apparently there have been explosions
nearby.
Um, Iran is using very interesting
tactics. Iran is using anamorphic
paintings on the ground fake to to show
fake military hardware like like
aircrafts and helicopters.
And the Israelis have been bombing those
paintings and releasing those videos on
Twitter. So you when you see the video,
there is this what looks like a
helicopter on the ground and it's hit by
a by a bomb. there's an explosion,
but the even the the blades of the
helicopter,
they remain intact. So, these are
paintings that look like actual objects,
anamorphic paintings. They're are being
struck by the idea by the Israeli
fighter planes and they're actually
releasing those videos and now people
are realizing this these were actually
paintings
and the Russians have also been using
the same tech the same techniques in the
Ukraine war. So it looks like a
significant portion of these supposedly
destroyed targets were paintings and
decoys.
Okay. Uh the global market is melting
down. Uh
about $3.2 trillion
of value has been wiped out from the
global market in 4 days. In South Korea,
there was a decline in their market of
12.1%.
Uh that was a disaster. the circuit
circuit the market shut down so fast
they had to break the circuit circuit
breaker was was triggered uh in Japan
there's been a disaster of the stock
market in Germany also in the UK also
the Dubai exchange crashed by 4.9%
uh crude oil is going up 83% $83 it's
gone up $83 and so much more India is a
major loser outside of the Middle East
uh India takes about $150 billion in
gulf oil imports and the Indian
population the expatriates Indian
expatriates who live in the Gulf every
year they send back about a hundred
billion dollars in rem remittances to
India
so India's economy
gets about a hundred billion dollar from
the Indians who live in the Gulf every
year that much money now if this
situation continues that will stop
that's going to hit the Indian economy
and again the Gulf oil that we are
purchasing $150 billion every year that
that is now at at ser serious risk. Now
is there a diplomatic solution possible?
Trump says that I said to they want to
talk but I said too late we can't talk
now. So and Iran has also said that we
will not have any negotiation
negotiations with the US after they
killed our supreme leader. So there is
no diplomatic solution possible now.
Yeah there is no diplomatic solution
possible now. Now some American senators
were given you know classified briefings
about what's really happening in the
war. And this senator called Elizabeth
Warren, she said after the classified
briefing about what she could speak to
the media, she said that the situation
is far worse than what anybody thinks.
The US administration, the Trump
administration has no plan. The war is
illegal and based on fact based on
falsehoods. That's what Elizabeth Warren
said to the media today. Okay. The
Canadian prime minister said that the
the American war may be inconsistent
with international law.
and Marco Rubio says that the attacks on
Iran will increase in hours and days.
Um, so that's the situation right now.
Okay, it's been a very long update by
me, but that overall is the situation.
Uh, is there anything else? So clearly
the US doctrine, military doctrine is
built for invasion,
but it it's it's failing against Iran.
Iran has a very clear pre-planned battle
strategy, war strategy. They've been
preparing for this war for 46 years.
Okay? They have done their homework.
They have planned for this thoroughly.
And the Americans and Israelis are
completely caught off guard by the scale
of Iran's response and the resilience of
the Iranian
response and military. Right. Um right
now there are no American warships in
the Gulf region. They've all moved out
otherwise they'll be wiped out. Okay?
And if they want resupply, if they want
to be resupplied to go go back to the
Gulf regular Garcia, 4 days one way,
four days back, 8 days. Okay.
And according to a Turkish admiral, Iran
has about 40,000 missiles, which is way
more than my estimate of 10,000
missiles, but maybe missiles of all
kinds. So that is a situation.
Iran is not losing this war.
Iran is going to fight fight fight until
the very bitter end if required. The
Americans can't defeat Iran. The
Israelis can't defeat Iran. Israel is
taking massive massive damage. From the
little bit I saw the videos from Tel
Aviv, it looks like that the Iranians
are turning Tel Aiv into Gaza.
So that is the situation and India is in
a tough tough spot.
India has chosen the side of the US and
Israel. Prime Minister Modi's statements
on Twitter and other places in the past
three four days make it very clear that
India has chosen the side of the US and
Israel
and now the US will want to force India
to give access
of Indian ports to their warships which
will make India a direct party in the
conflict against Iran.
Does India have the fortitude,
the resilience to say no to the US or
has India already said yes? I don't know
right now but this is the situation.
Okay. Variety topics says where do you
get the information from? I get the
information from open sources from the
public domain
right not one source hundreds of
sources.
Okay. Now let's take some questions.
Ritik P says did the US and Israel
underestimate Iran?
They underestimated Iran very badly.
Very badly. Very catastrophically.
Mr. Rohit says the US sank a Iranian
ship Dina days after it left Vishaka
Padnam from the Milan 2026 exercises in
the Indian Ocean. Could India have
stopped it for regional security? Was
India aware of the strike? India was
aware of nothing. India was in the dark.
The Americans will not tell India what
they're going to do.
Why will they tell India about anything?
India was not told about this. But this
happened in our backyard in a in a in a
region that that essentially India
claims it is our strategic backyard.
India has this fantastic slogan right
the Indian Ocean region is our strategic
backyard.
So this happened in our backyard off the
coast of Sri Lanka which is right next
door to us. It actually comes under our
our jurisdiction essentially of the
Indian Navy. Not djour but de facto
right. And the ship, the Iranian ship
was returning to Iran from India.
Could India have stopped this? India
would not dare to stop it even if it
knew.
We for Valer says, "Thank you for your
courage and love of Dharma." Thank you
very much, sir. Thank you very much.
Struggler says, "Seems like someone
wants to drag us into a war." Seems like
someone does want to drag drag us into a
war. Yes.
Alkash Shikari says is US aircraft
carrier near Indian Ocean and taking
supplies from Mumbai port. I can't
answer that question because I don't
have the knowledge. It is definitely in
the western Indian Ocean the so-called
Arabian Sea region. Let me show you.
So the US aircraft carrier is somewhere
in this region somewhere. Okay. Maybe
between the coasts of Gujarat and Oman.
Maybe closer to Gujarat than Oman. will
be closer to Mumbai than to Oman
possibly. I can't possibly say because I
am not aware. I don't have the real-time
location of the aircraft carrier. But it
has moved out of the vicinity of of the
straight of Hormuz and it is perhaps
somewhere in the closer to India
possibly in the so-called Arabian Sea
region. That is where it is. Is it
taking supplies from Mumbai port? I
can't possibly say because I don't know.
I am not aware. The government of India
will be aware of what's happening. I am
not aware.
Mitra Singh Chadasama says what's your
predictions of war and world after war
predictions look
this war is going to escalate
the Americans may force European nations
to get involved in this the UK uh
Germany
France
France is it already involved are Rafals
flying over the UAE over Dubai I don't
know it's possible
If the French get involved, if the
European nations get involved and there
are direct hits on their assets by Iran,
then that's direct warfare. So then more
nations are involved. If the Americans
forcibly drag India into the war, then
India is involved. This is in our
backyard.
The Gulf is next door to India by the
way.
So if more nations get involved then
there is even more pressure on Iran for
example
then Russia and China will have to get
involved because Russia and China cannot
afford to lose Iran.
So how can China is we know it's it's
far away geographically from Iran right
see if you look here there's a
significant distance between China and
Iran and there's no way China can access
Iran and supply Iran unless it is by
flights you know cargo planes but what
about Russia Russia Russian territory
I'll tell you what it's how far from the
750 km from the maybe 700 km from the
Iranian coast coastline uh in in the
Caspian Sea
The shortest distance is about 450 km
roughly.
So Russia can certainly resupply Iran
through the Caspian Sea through airspace
and so on. Right? So if more nations get
involved, if the European nations get
involved, if India is dragged into this
matter and then if Russia decides it it
is also getting involved, then you have
a situation where you you half the world
is fighting. What do you call the
situation? You call it World War II.
after war. I have no idea. But this can
drag us into World War II right now.
This situation
team talks says US goals are shifting
from regime change to obliteration of
their missile capabilities. Does
superpower also have shortcomings? The
superpower has shortcomings. They are
very visible right now. Clearly visible
shortcomings. First of all, they didn't
plan properly. Second, they were
overconfident. Third, the
doctrine is geared for um is it's geared
for
uh deterrence against the superpower
which no longer exists. Their war
fighting doctrine is still the 20th
century cold war doctrine.
What does the US do when it fights a
war? It invades if it first obliterates
and flattens a nation through air power,
then sends in troops. But in this case,
they can't do it. they are unable to do
it. They don't have the wherewithal to
send troops into Iran.
So,
so they are in a situation where they
can't really do what they are used to
doing and they don't know what to, you
know, they don't have a plan B.
Their plan B could be to drag to keep
the go war going on for for months,
maybe years, and then hope from their
perspective hopefully balcanize Iran.
they will want to bulcanize Iran if they
can't do regime change. So maybe there
is the next plan and Trump has already
said that we will support the Kuresh
militias and all who who will fight the
government of Iran on on our behalf. So
they they want to weaponize the various
ethnic groups non-Persian ethnic groups
in Iran and the long-term strategy is to
balconize Iran. Well, that will take
years to to actually make to to actually
uh engineer
months or years and there's no guarantee
of success there. So yeah, there are
major shortcomings in what they're doing
capabilities. Ritik says, "Are Houthi
terrorists similar to Hamas and Hisbah?"
No, Houthis are not similar to Hamas and
Hisbullah. Hamas is a terrorist outfit.
Hamas carried out the October what
October
2023 strike terrorist attack against
against Israeli civilians. Barbaric
inhuman attack on Israeli civilians.
Hamas is is is a bunch of monsters.
Hamas is like Pakistanis.
That's what Hamas is. Hisbollah also
have similar tendencies. I I believe his
are based out of Lebanon. Hamas are
actually Sunnis. Hisbah are Shia. Uh
Hisbah also you can possibly consider
them to be terrorists. Houthis
don't [snorts] classify as terrorists.
The Houthis are essentially the
government of a certain portion of Yemen
and all they want is to be left alone
just like the Taliban. Leave us alone.
Allow us to rule our country the way we
want and you stay out of it. That's all
they want. The Houthis.
And there's been a war on Yemen by the
US and their vasals for decades.
For decades. If you want to understand
the situation in Yemen because very few
people understand it and it's not your
fault because no one speaks about this.
I'll tell you what how to find out about
Yemen what the situation really is.
Okay, give me a second.
Give me a second. So if you go to
if you go to my channel okay on my
channel I have done
two podcasts. So here is the playlist of
podcasts on my channel. Okay. And one of
you have to go back all the way to the
beginning.
Okay.
And there is this podcast with Dr. Issa
Blumi.
A Bijit Cha podcast episode 13. It's
it's more than 2 hours long. But if you
want to understand the history, the
recent history of Yemen and how Yemen
has been destroyed,
brutalized by the US and the US Vas. and
watch that podcast. You will get get a
good amount of understanding from from
watching that podcast.
So, Houthies are not terrorists.
Uh sorry, Agam Senpai says, "Professor
Jang May 2024 predicted one, Trump wins
the election. Second, the US starts Iran
war. Third, the US loses. Fourth, no
regime change without grant invasion or
bribe. How true are three or four?"
Three and four. Okay. First is Trump
wins election that happened. The US
starts a war in Iran. They have started
it. Israel started it, but the US got
involved. Sure. Third, the US loses this
war. It looks likely the US will not
achieve its objectives. On day one,
Trump said he wants regime change. And
he said to the people of Iran, be
prepared. In a short while, you will be
able to take out the government.
That's what he said on on day one of of
this war. Now, he is saying, "No, no,
no, no, no regime change. We just want
to demilitarize Iran and so on so forth,
whatever else, some other." So he has
shifted the goalposts now
but even that
even that to achieve even that will take
months if not years
and if it doesn't happen in the next 2
three weeks Trump looks like a like a
complete fool in in front of the
American public
so what does Trump do now it's a loss if
you don't achieve your objectives it's a
loss it's a loss
most likely the Americans are losing
this war by not achieving their
objectives.
Yeah. Uh number four is no regime change
without ground invasion of bribe. Oh,
absolutely true. You can't achieve a
regime change through bombardments,
aerial bombardments and aerial uh
campaigns. You have to put boots on the
ground to affect an actual regime change
or you have to bribe somebody.
Uh they were able to do that in
Venezuela. They did not put boots on the
ground, but they were able to bribe
Venezuela. Essentially that's what
happened right they took out Maduro
kidnapped him without actually having to
do much military action.
So it's you will it will either take a
ground invasion or you they will have to
bribe uh the the key people in the
Iranian government and even that looks
unlikely. So I think three is correct.
Three will turn out to be correct. Most
likely the US will lose this war. It
will not achieve its objectives and
regime change I don't see it happening.
So yeah
uh Pratar Dhana says I am very
disappointed. I condemn those Indians
celebrating the death of 160 Iranian
Iranian children.
Uh rest in peace for little girls. Are
Indians are some Indians celebrating the
murder of those 160 little girls?
I I I have not seen that. If someone is
doing that they are
>> I don't even have words to say to them.
Obviously, it's condemnable if if anyone
is celebrating the death of those girls.
Really, I was not aware of this. That's
terrible. If if that's happening,
terrible.
Black Panther says, "I if this Iran war
will go long for more than 6 months, the
US will get significantly weaker. Next,
China and Russia go with the stray same
strategy to attack US assets."
Okay, that's your prediction, is it?
that if this goes on for six months this
is what this is what will happen um this
will go on the Americans are not going
to achieve their objectives anytime soon
even the goalposts after they have
changed and Trump says that no we don't
want regime change we want something
else even that is not possible
anytime soon anytime soon
I don't see the Americans achieving any
of their objectives
in 6 months or even one year even one
year so if that happens will Russia and
China go with the same strategy to
attack US assets
for China it's Taiwan China has no
interest in attacking anybody else China
wants Taiwan Taiwan Taiwan can China
take Taiwan
that is I I doubt it
says if Iran threat ends then who will
buy America's weapons and Gulf look Iran
is not a threat to anyone the Americans
have positioned Iran as a threat and
they have encircled Iran with military
bases that's why the whole region is
militarized and and volatile and tense.
And of course, there's the Israel
factor, which is a different story. So,
if this so-called Iran threat ends, then
who will buy America's weapons in the
Gulf?
They'll find somebody to buy it. See,
after the USSR threat ended, people kept
buying American weapons, right? So, the
Americans will find ways of ways for of
selling their weapons. Don't worry about
that. [laughter]
Uh, okay. Prardana says, "It's a RIP for
West Asia. Bahin may fall too.
Bahin is this little thing, right?
Where's the map? Where is map? So, let's
go to the map. Um,
so
see Bahin is this little little little
little island here. Little it's even
tinier than Qatar.
Tiny.
And the Americans have the headquarters
of their fifth fleet over here near
Manama.
near Manama
and that's that infrastructure has been
significantly damaged by the Iranians.
Uh but I don't think the Iranians will
take Bahrain and and you know invade
Bahrain and occupy Bahin. I don't think
Iran has any such intentions.
Uh so Bahrain obviously will get damaged
etc. But I don't see Bahin falling as in
Iran occupying Bahin that I don't see
that happening. But apart from that what
you're saying is correct. RIP for West
Asia.
See the entire West Asia paradigm. You
see you have these beautiful nations
like the UAE etc. very peaceful nations,
tremendous law and order,
extremely high standards,
extremely fabulously wealthy cities like
Dubai, Abu Dhabi etc.
These cities are see Dubai etc are are
positioned as the Switzerland of West
Asia. that if you are a wealthy person
then come and invest in Dubai, buy
property, come and live in Dubai. You
will get the best luxury in the world.
You'll get the best lifestyle in the
world. You will have to pay zero taxes
and you'll meet lots of rich and
like-minded people and so on. So so many
people from across the world, they live
in in cities like Dubai, in a city like
Dubai because they get so many wonderful
benefits. Lots of Indians live there. I
suppose most Indians will know somebody
or the other, their family or outside or
whatever. But most Indians will know
somebody or the other who lives in the
UAE in Dubai or in West Asia. That model
is now destroyed. See the that model
relied on an American promise.
The American promise was you guys don't
worry about your your national defense.
We will take care of your national
defense. You build up your cities and do
all the fantastic things you want. And
we Americans, we have all these military
bases here. We will guarantee your
security. That is the promise the
Americans have given them. And that's
why these nations have not invested in
self-defense, national defense. They
have simply invested all their money
into building up these cities and the
infrastructure and all that.
Now they have realized this American
promise was a lie. America had no
intention of defending these countries.
These American military bases were not
the infrastructure of defense. It was
the infrastructure of occupation and
America is only concerned with the
defense of Israel.
That's what that's the realization
that's coming in now. And you have Dubai
being bombed. You have hotels in Dubai
where American soldiers and personnel
were stay staying. Those hotels were
taken out were hit by drones and
missiles. you had at least one tragic
death in Abu Dhabi. When you have a
situation like this and this continues,
if it happens once and stops after a
week, nobody people will say, "Okay, it
was a one-off thing." But if this
continues and escalates, escalates,
escalates over, escalates over months
and years, the entire
economic model of West Asia will
collapse and everybody who had invested
in Abu Dhabi, who was living in Abu
Dhabi or Dubai or wherever, they will
all leave permanently.
Christian already left.
So that is the end of the hopes and
dreams of these
nations. Who's to blame? The US.
Shishni Siliguri says if one country
uses a nuclear weapon against another,
how would it actually impact the entire
world?
Well, one nuclear weapon being used
somewhere
won't impact the entire world.
Obviously, it will horrify the world
because using a nuclear weapon against
anyone is a war crime. It's a crime
against humanity.
It is barbaric to use a nuclear weapon.
But if a nuclear weapon is used
somewhere, it won't affect the entire
world. It won't impact the entire world.
If multiple nuclear weapons are used
then there will be radioactive fallout
that goes into the atmosphere
substantial amount of radioactive
fallout and it could cause you know
radiation uh the spread of radiation
across a large part of the globe that's
a possibility.
So here's the scenario. If things don't
go well for the US, the US is not able
to make any headway and Israel is
getting pounded repeatedly
and Hormuz remains closed
and American infrastructure is taken out
and let's say an American aircraft
carrier is taken out then Trump will be
very tempted to use nuclear weapons on
on Iran.
So let's say Trump uses nuclear weapons.
What happens then?
Well, Iran will keep fighting. Even if
Trump detonates 10 nuclear warheads on
Iran, Iran will still keep fighting as
if nothing has happened. That's the deal
about Iran.
But if Trump does this,
then
what can other nations do?
I suppose Russia could get involved in
this. But then you don't want a USRussia
direct confrontation because that is
like doomsday for the world. So the
point is if one or two weapons are used
even 10 weapons are used it will not
really impact the entire world too much.
There will be some radiation exposure to
the world but nothing that will cause
significant danger. Maybe in some some
regions there will be a higher chance of
cancer
but beyond that nothing much. But
consider a totally different scenario.
Okay totally different. Let's say the US
and Russia directly get involved for
some reason
and there's a nuclear exchange for some
reason.
If Russia or the US launch even one
nuclear weapon at the other one, there
will be immediate retaliation from the
other side.
Now if if
the US launches first and Russia
retaliates and the Americans see this
bioc missile coming in then they will
launch more and the Russians will see
more are coming towards us we'll launch
more and within minutes you'll have
hundreds of nuclear weapons being
launched and these nuclear missiles
these ballistic missiles they are not
standard ballistic missiles they are
MIRV missiles they have multiple
independently targetable re-entry
vehicles
So one missile can carry can carry 10
warheads and they all go after
re-entering the atmosphere in totally
different directions. So it's very hard
to bring them down. So in a matter of 30
40 minutes you will have hundreds
possibly thousands of nuclear
explosions.
Okay. Now when a nuclear explosion
happens you will have a fireball. Let's
say it's a standard fishision device
uranium 235 or plutonium whatever a fish
device. So you'll have a fireball very
high temperature maybe millions of
degrees C and there'll be a certain
blast radius within which everything
becomes vaporized. This fireball expands
then it rises because it's it's very
hot. It's hotter than the air. So it
rises. When it starts rising it pulls in
all the vaporized rock, all the
vaporized dust, all the debris from the
from kilometers around it. It sucks it
all in and pulls it up into the
atmosphere. That's how you have a
mushroom cloud. Now, if you have
hundreds, maybe thousands of mushroom
clouds, you'll have millions of tons of
vaporized rock and and and dust and all
kinds of other particles and debris
rising high into the atmosphere and that
will remain in the atmosphere for maybe
several years, maybe a decade. Because
of that, the surface of our planet will
not receive direct sunlight for that
much time, maybe a decade. So
temperatures go down drastically maybe
10 20° C in a matter of hours.
So if you are staying in Chennai
by tomorrow morning it will start
snowing in Chennai.
That's the situation you will have. It's
called a nuclear winter. There will be
no sunlight for a decade. All the plants
will die without sunlight and
photosynthesis. If the plants die,
humans die and and carniv and
herbivorous animals die. If her
herbivorous animals die, carnivorous
animals die. And there's going to be a
global mass extinction event.
Maybe 95% of humanity will die out.
That's the kind of impact you have if
there is a massive nuclear exchange plus
the nuclear plus the radiation which
will cause all kinds of other other
problems. So a nuclear winter is what
happens when you have massive nuclear
exchange. It's a disaster beyond your
imagination.
And that's the direction in which Trump
is dragging us today.
Aniket says, "Is the US reviving
Islam in Iran? Because Islam was in
decline in Iran, but attacking Iran
would only make people stand with the
regime again and the US can sell its
weapons." The US is not doing this for
reviving Iran. Islam in Iran. It may be
an unintended consequence perhaps. See,
Islam, I suppose it wasn't declining in
Iran because it's not an Iranian
religion anyway. It's not the religion
of the Persians. It was imposed upon
them. uh but they have attacked Iran and
this will make people stand with the
regime. It doesn't make people become
Islamic again right the people will have
no option but to stand with the regime
because the regime is defending the
country and the country is under assault
by the Americans. So even those who were
in favor of the Americans will start
have to stand with the regime because
they are being bombarded and their
children are being bombarded by the by
the Americans and the Israelis. So this
will make people rally around the regime
and and fight for the country whether
they believe in Islam or not but it
won't necessarily revive Islam unless
this drags them for 10 years or
something then something may happen.
Alkash alkashari says what can India
learn from Iran? Good question. What can
India learn from this? See the war. Why
is Iran able to stand and fight? Iran is
able to stand and fight today because it
has more than a 100,000 drones. First of
all, Shahed two drones. What does the
Shahed 2 drone look like?
Let me show you. It's a cheap thing. 10,
20,000, $30,000.
Shahed drone, right? Shahed drones. What
do they look like?
This is what these things look like.
Shahed drones. This is an actual image
of a Shahed drone. It's got a propeller
behind it behind its uh backside. That's
a Shahed drone. Cheap thing and you can
produce hundreds of thousands of these.
So, one component of their self national
defense is the Shahed drones. The second
thing that is going for Iran, going well
for Iran is that it has perhaps more
than 10,000 ballistic missiles.
It has the it it has this massive
stockpiles
of drones and missiles. That's why it's
able to fight. Now, how many ballistic
missiles does India have?
India has designated its ballistic
missiles, AGNI and all that as the
carriers of its nuclear deterrent but
not as conventional weapons. So if India
let's say hypothetically has 500
warheads nuclear warheads hypothetically
then India may have at most 500
ballistic missiles.
Okay. So what India needs to do it needs
to transform its ballistic missiles into
a conventional weapon as well. And India
needs to have a stockpile of maybe 30
40,000 missiles of various kinds
including ballistic missiles including
cruise missiles hypersonics and all
that. A nation of India's size, it has
to defend this much larger terri
territory than Iran. India needs tens of
thousands of missiles of various kinds
and it needs lacks of drones.
That is what Iran India can learn from
Iran. If hypothetically there's a war
tomorrow with somebody, let's say China,
how will you target the Chinese
infrastructure? The Chinese
infrastructure is thousands of
kilometers from India. Next to India,
you have open empty territory. Tibet and
whatnot, Shinjang and etc. There are no
big cities there. There's no
manufacturing happening there. The
Chinese manufacturing uh heartland is
far in the east of China. How does India
target that if there's a war? The
Chinese will be targeting India's
infrastructure from Tibet. But how do we
target the Chinese infrastructure? We
will need tens of thousands of ballistic
missiles and hundreds of thousands of
drones.
Does India have a drone like the Shahed
too? No.
The Americans have also copied the
shahad to the shahad drone.
They've learned
we
I think we are now making a shishnag
drone or something. We have suddenly
woken up. Okay.
Shishnag drone
India's quiet entry 10 hours ago. So 10
hours ago India woke up
or maybe a week ago India woke up.
Yeah. The sheshnag drone. It is
something that resembles the shahed,
right?
So finally India is waking up. But how
many do we have? That's the question.
India needs a few slaps in it face in
its face before it wakes up for
anything. This is the problem with
India. Who do you blame for this?
Okay. Abisheku says is nuke going to be
used? Well, first of all, I hope nukes
are never used. But I think that in this
war there is a higher likelihood that
someone like Trump may be tempted to use
nukes if things don't go his way.
So I I hope I hope it doesn't happen but
the Americans may use nukes possibly.
Ammon George says good to see you sir.
Thank you so much. How does their
missile city work? The Iranians need to
bring their launchers to the surface to
fire. Right. The US could bomb entrance.
So these missile cities, so the
Iranians, their missiles, their
stockpiles, all of that, none of that is
on the surface of the planet. It's all
deep underground. Why is it all deep
underground? So that they can save safe
safeguard the missiles and all the
infrastructure from the American
bombings. The Americans want to destroy
everything Iran has. So that's why Iran
has taken everything deep underground.
Now, how deep underground? Definitely
deeper than 50 m. See, the Americans
have this bunker buster bombs that can
destroy targets as deep as 50 m
underground. Let's find out how deep can
how Oh, no.
How deep can American bunker buster
bombs penetrate?
Oh, don't work. How deep
can American bunker busters go? All
right.
um 60 plus mters. Okay,
60 m or something. So the Iranian
infrastructure will be perhaps 100 m
below the surface, something like that.
So they've built up entire cities and
networks of tunnels all across Iran
where they are storing these missiles
and drones and all that. And obviously
when they want to launch a missile, they
have to bring it out
above the surface and quickly launch it.
So the Americans and Israelis are
monitoring Iran 24 by7. The Americans
are using low earth orbit satellites to
constantly monitor Iran. They're using
various other methods of surveillance.
And they are trying to find out where
these missiles are being launched from.
You can also study the the the exhaust
the exhaust streak right the streak that
comes from the exhaust of a missile. So
by doing that you can find out where the
missiles are being launched for from and
they can immediately bomb those places
so that you can possibly hopefully
destroy maybe the launcher or maybe
destroy the place the the entrance of
the tunnels and and that sort of thing.
So the Iranians obviously have
anticipated that that's why they have
these TEL vehicles or vehicles
transporter erector launcher vehicles
which are essentially trucks on which
you have missiles and then the missile
will stand up like that and it will be
launched and then the truck disappears
as fast as possible. It moves as fast as
possible. So there is no loca set
location from where the missile is
launched. That that that's what you can
do. You can take the missile out, put it
on a truck in the night, then take it a
few kilometers away or whatever, a
couple of hours away, launch it, and
then have the truck go away faster. So,
it's a game of cat and mouse. But if the
Americans bomb the entrance of the of
the tunnels, then the Iranians will have
to spend a lot of time clearing up the
debris and rubble and once again opening
up the entrances. So, once again, it's a
game of cat and mouse. That is what's
going on right now.
Team talks says Japan was not
surrendering. The US nuked them. Is Iran
becoming a second Japan today? Iran
launched a missile on Turkey. Why is it
becoming scarier? It's becoming scarier.
Let me see. Has Iran launched a missile
on Turkey?
Okay, one second. Has Iran launched
a missile
on Turkey?
Uh Turkey says missile destroyed.
Turkey and NATO intercept a missile.
Okay,
looks like there is there something has
happened but I am not 100% sure. I have
to perhaps look somewhere else. Maybe I
should look at uh Twitter. Let's see.
Give me a second.
I have Twitter open. Okay, one second.
Let me see on Twitter.
All right.
Here
we have Twitter. What do we have? Let's
see.
Turkey missile.
Do we have something? A ballistic
missile heading towards Turkish airspace
passing through Iraqi and Syrian
airspace was successfully engaged and
neutralized by NATO air and missile
defense elements in the eastern
Mediterranean.
This is old. Okay. Yeah. So, looks like
that's happened. Yeah. Um Yeah. So,
looks like uh a missile was being
launched towards Turkey, but it's been
intercepted by NATO.
Um,
so Japan was not surrendering and the US
nuked them. Is Iran becoming a second
Japan? Well, I think it's still early
days. I think it's still too early to
say to say whether Japan is becoming
whether Iran is becoming the next Japan.
But Trump may be tempted to use nuclear
weapons at some point in time in this
war.
Rid Naran Singh says after Iran Anglo
Aim is nuclear free India Pakistan
already in shambles US monitors their
nukes for India northeast Punjab Kashmir
Dravidian Hindu Muslim cast OBC general
cast SCST language fault lines too many
well you see if the Americans are able
to win the war against Iran their focus
will then immediately move towards
India.
India is next.
The Americans want to balconize Iran and
they want to balkcanize India. Right now
they will use India. They'll arm twist
India into giving access to India's
ports to the Americans. They'll use
India right now. But afterwards they
will focus on India. They they will want
to bulkerize India. And there are too
many fault lines in India which have
been created by the British and which
have been
maintained by the governments of India
since 1947 and and and made worse. Those
fault lines have been exacerbated by
successive governments after 1947.
Right?
So there is the far east of India, the
northeast of India, the Manipur issue,
Manipur, half at least half of Manipur
is under foreign occupation right now.
There is the whatever is happening in
Punjab the Kalistthan thing is there
then there's the industrial scale
Christian conversions in Punjab there is
the Kashmir thing there is the Dravidian
versus Arian thing the Arian invasion
thing is the cause because of that Hindu
Muslim cast divide Hindus among cast
also by by making one set of people
permanent oppressors and one set of
people permanent permanently oppressed
language for lines
the
These problems exist because the
governments after 1947 did not fix these
problems.
Uh yeah. So after Iran, if the Americans
win in Iran, they're coming for India
next. That is a guarantee.
One says attack on the Iranian warship
Dina, is it not betrayal on our end?
It's not. It was not in Indian
territorial waters anymore.
It was off the coast of Sri Lanka. Gal,
right? Where was where did this happen?
Let me quickly take a look roughly.
Um,
is it Gaul? Is it Gal? Was it? What is
it? That city? Never been there.
Uh, see the southernmost part of Sri
Lanka. Southern tip of Sri Lanka. this
city gal or gal the warship Iranian
warship was brought was was struck by a
torpedo somewhere in this region I don't
know if it's in Sri Lankan waters or
international waters but somewhere here
this that's what happened that obviously
is no longer in Indian territorial
waters right
so if the American if if if an American
submarine torpedoed an Iranian warship
outside of Indian territorial waters
it's not a betrayal by India
but it's definitely an attempt by
America would drag India into the matter
because the ship was coming from India.
Okay, so it's not a betrayal by India.
No. As Modi kissed the boat, this is
unacceptable. Nobody will take us
seriously. How can we allow American
submarines so close and attack our
guests? See, once the Iranian warship
left Indian waters, it was no longer our
guest. It was there in international
waters. So technically, nobody can blame
India and this happened near Sri Lanka,
more not near India. But because India
has this wonderful slogan which we love
to repeat all the time. The Indian Ocean
is our strategic backyard. That's why I
said this happened in our strategic
backyard.
But obviously the Indian Navy doesn't
really patrol that region. The Indian
Navy is mostly patrolling our coasts if
at all. Right? So how can we allow
American submarines?
Tomorrow morning if American submarines
enter India's ter territorial waters,
India can't do a thing about that.
Even if they break international law in
enter Indian territorial waters, India
can't do a thing about that. Why is
that? Is it because Modi is weak? No,
it's because India is weak. India had 75
years, 80 years to build up its
strength, but we have never bothered to
do that.
Yeah. So that's that's what it is. And
obviously when you are weak, people
don't take you seriously.
You can put laser eyes on your leaders
and all but people don't take you
seriously. Words don't matter. Actions
matter. And look at the actions.
Feels strong man says Mr. Abijit Cha
please understand that I had to super
slam
super slam your bro because he would
have hit me back if and when my cousin
would have whacked your What are you
talking about? What's a super slam?
I had to super slam your bro
because he would have hit me back if and
when my cousin would have whacked yours.
What are you talking about, sir? I have
no idea. I have absolutely no. What's a
super slam?
Does super slam mean something? Is it
slang for something? What is the deal?
What is a super slam? Let me see. Uh
super slam.
It's a game.
Super Slam, SummerSlam.
Okay, I have no idea what you're talking
about. Which bro are you talking about?
Which cousin? I I am clueless. Sorry.
Prattana says government is now running
back to Russia like fools.
Yeah. Oil. Yeah. Swastik Shankar says if
Iran falls, people say only three
countries are left. Russia, China, and
India.
with modern technology narratives,
economic compromise, fault lines. Either
we become like Iran like regime or go
full vasal nuke surrender hosting bases.
If Iran falls,
it's Russia and China that's left.
Okay?
India has already picked a side
and if India is hosting American
warships already I don't know if we are
doing that but if we start doing that
well then
well then it's two two nations left
Russia and China only yeah
I don't think we will surrender nukes
even if we become vasals but those nukes
will be decorative art items
only for decoration in that case in that
hypothetical case. Okay. So
hypotheticals
Asha says you have always been critical
of NU and Indian National Congress. You
should thank Nero that we followed
non-aligned movement and thus never
compromise our sovereignty while Prime
Minister Modi the weakest prime minister
could not even criticize Trump.
Thank you for your Thank you very much
for your opinion and your perspective
sir. I respect your opinion. Thank you
sir.
Libyk says if Iran supports Hamas then
Iran terrorist no if America supports
Pakistan is America terrorist nation if
America installs al-Qaeda or ISIS
terrorist as the prime as the president
of Syria is America terrorist nation
does anybody call America a terrorist
nation or a state sponsor of terrorism
nobody does
nobody does America plays Chanekiti at
the highest level
at the highest level
they have funded and financed Pakistani
terrorism against India for decades
since the 1980s
but you won't call America that right so
why do you want to call Iran whatever
Iran is playing the same game that
America plays
exact same game but you want to call
Iran terrorist but not the other one why
please
black Panther says is this the right
time for China to take over Taiwan. It's
the worst possible time.
Worst possible time. There is no oil
flowing from hormones.
About 30 to 40% of China's oil minimum
comes from hormones. More. More. Let's
see. Let's see. Let's see. Let's find
out. Okay.
What percentage of China's oil comes
from the Persian Gulf region?
Uh, are they not Iran? Persian Gulf.
Let's see. Visual capitalist. What does
it say? Um by country. Okay, we are not
getting the answer here.
Uh okay, so maybe 40 because see it's
Kuwait, it's UAE, it's Saudi Arabia,
it's Oman, Oman is on the other side,
UAE, Kuwait, Saudi Arabia and Iran.
Probably 40 50% of China's oil comes
from this region. So when that is
stopped, you think China will make a
move on Taiwan?
I think it's a it's a very bad time for
China to try this. Very bad time. Not a
good time.
Praradhana says, "I think Iran may have
a better education system than us." You
mean India? Oh, 100%.
Iran's education system is far superior
to India's education system. Yep.
Sora modil says how alarmed should India
be with her internal security looking at
the protests in Kashmir Lacna etc.
You mean the protests against the
American action on on Iran? I don't
think that's a big national security
concern. Those are protests against the
US, not against India, right? But
overall internal security, we have to
take it very seriously. And we obviously
have big issues, big issues in various
parts of India. No question about that.
Open to unlearn. That's a great name.
So the question or the question is is it
fair to say that if our education system
was capable of speaking speaking the
truth and make the population patriotic
this will stop corruption.
It will definitely have a significant
positive impact in uh rooting out
corruption.
Right? It certainly would if the
education system was much better and you
could actually speak the truth.
It would definitely make a big
difference for sure. Yes. Because see
there are so many things about our
history that we can't even speak openly
about in the education. The education
system tiptoes around those topics.
It skirts those topics. We can't even
speak openly about our history and
what's happened in the past. We can't
speak openly about it. We can't discuss
the actions of foreigners openly.
So that
that puts in this culture of
self-censorship in in everybody and uh
it it teaches you lies about history
which makes you less patriotic. It puts
this huge burden of the inferiority
complex on all Indians.
Right? All Indians have this inferiority
complex.
You weren't born with an inferiority
complex but today you have it. The
education system does that to you. So
yeah, the education system definitely
needs to be reformed.
Fields strong man says, "I see many
China bots commenting negative in every
video of yours." Well, it's the second
largest population in the world. They'll
come, right? It's okay. Let them do it.
Let them do it. It's fine.
Aniket says
CZ remains the largest supplier of crude
to India. CZ
in February. India's Russia Russian oil
impose climbed 6% in February despite US
pressure plus buying more S400 anti
vasal behavior. What's say CZ
Czechoslovakia
CZ
uh okay somebody is the largest supplier
of food to India. So India is buying
more S400s that is that is not behavior.
So that is that is the behavior of a
sovereign nation because the Americans
don't like India buying such things but
we are still buying it. Good. I'm glad.
I'm glad. But there are other behaviors
that raise big question marks. So I'm
I'm very glad we are buying more S400s.
I'm very glad.
Magnesium supplements is US arming
Kuresh for ground operations. Is this a
right move? Well, it's right for the US.
It's bad. It's wrong for Iran, but it's
not happened yet. It's only words thus
far. Trump says that he will consider
doing it or he's thinking of doing it of
supporting Kurdish aspirations, Kish
Kuresh aspirations for independence from
Iran. So he is saying I want to ferment
a civil war in Iran. That's what he is
saying. He has not started arming them
yet and it will be difficult because the
this will set off big alarm bells in
Turkey. So the Turks will oppose this.
So it's it's just conceptual right now.
It's not happened. Black Panther says,
"How can how the US can defeat Iran in
this war?" Nuclear option. See, even if
they use nuclear weapons, Iran will not
be defeated.
Let's say one nuke kills 10,000 people.
Okay?
And [clears throat] let's say the
Americans use 10 nukes. Okay? I I don't
want any nuclear use, but I'm just
saying hypothetically. So, if there are
10 nukes that are used, maybe it'll
it'll kill a 100,000 people, maybe a
million people. The Iranians will still
keep fighting.
The US can't defeat Iran unless they
create a a horrible water shortage in
Iran or something. Then Iran could be
balconized possibly, but that will take
several years. The Americans can't
defeat Iran, aren't the Iranians are
willing to fight handto hand at the end
if required. They'll fight with sticks
and stones and knives and swords if
required. The Americans can't defeat
Iran. Saddam Hussein tried for 10 years
with all his might and you know what who
was funding and arming the Saddam
Hussein? The US
and Saddam failed and he is right next
door. The Americans are far away. How
will they bring so much manpower and
all? Not possible.
Rohani says the world is clearly
overdependent on the straight of
hormones. Will we see new trade routes
open up? Which nations could potentially
benefit from them? See, when it comes to
oil, there's only one place.
There's only one place which has the
majority of the oil in the world. That's
the Persian Gulf region.
Now, if you find other oil reserves
elsewhere, then those new trade routes
could open up. But as long as the
majority of the world's oil is
physically present in the Persian Gulf
region, you can't get do anything about
the dependency on the straight of
Hormuz. You can't do anything about it.
This is not a trade route. It's an
energy supply route.
And the trade you can do anywhere. But
energy if it is only located there or
majority of it is located there, you
can't bypass the state of Hormos, right?
Um so yeah,
new energy routes, I don't see them
opening up. Uh we have some other
nations like uh
we have African nations, Nigeria, etc.
which produce oil. Indonesia as an oil
producer.
Um
what else? Venezuela.
Uh next to Venezuela, what's that
country where the Guyana right? Guyana
has discovered major oil oil reserves.
Guyana could be a potential candidate
and so on. But yeah, you you can't do
anything about the state of Horus
because the oil is physically located in
that region.
Rida Narayan Singh says if they are done
with Iran they will make minority in
danger narrative by American newspapers
NOS's Pakistan Sunni Iran Saudi Turkey
will come if come for India and US will
make pressure in world for India to
demilitarize and rock news what is the
question
if they are done with Iran they will
make minority endangered narrative take
okay US newspapers NGOs and so on fine
Pakistan Sunni Iran Saudi Turkey If come
for India and US will make pressure in
the world for India to deamilize and
drop nukes nukes like Japan. I don't see
nukes getting involved in this matter.
Okay. So let's say the Americans are
able to get what they want achieve what
they want in Iran. Okay. Then they will
come after India but not with nuclear
weapons.
Not with nuclear weapons.
They will work. There are already these
massive divisions in India
which have been actually made worse by
successive Indian governments right the
Americans will work on that they will do
subnational diplomacy they will they
will create all kinds of narratives of
minorities and the under and in danger
and all that stuff uh they will make the
situation in Manipur worse they'll make
the situation in other parts of India
worse and they'll have India break up
eventually that's the that's the dream
goal so it will need nukes for that to
happen.
Aries Manticor says, "I have seen Iran's
recent statements. They don't seem to
openly mind India's current stance. They
seem strangely silent, too. We aren't
angry at each other. We seem strangely
aligned in mutual silence. [laughter]
See, understand one thing.
India has done absolutely nothing
in the past four days against Iran.
Understand
the difference between words and
actions. Prime Minister Modi's tweets
are words.
His absence of a tweet condo condoling
the death of Mr. Kamei that's also words
or the absence of words.
Words nobody cares. See Indians care
about words but in the real world nobody
cares about words.
Okay. Iran will understand that India is
making statements. They're doing because
of various compulsions and constraints
they face. But India is not actually
doing anything against us. India is not
taking any action that can hurt us.
Right? So that's why Iran doesn't mind.
India is verbally supporting Israel, the
US and the Gulf nations verbally
verbally. We are not sending arms,
ammunition, weapons to those countries.
We are not sending Akash missiles and
brahos missiles to various nations. We
are staying out of it. So you understand
that? Do you understand that? So words
don't matter in India. Words matter. In
India only words matter. Indians only
look at words. They don't
all Indians are all about words. Words
don't matter. So thus far India has
taken no actions that can hurt Iran
that's why Iran doesn't mind. But if
India if India starts allowing American
warships to to dock in Indian ports
that's a whole different story and the
Americans will will demand that.
Prahep says can India start buying
Russian oil again? I think India has no
choice but to buy Russian oil. No choice
whatsoever.
India always has the option to do it but
India has stopped doing it allegedly of
late because Uncle Trump is unhappy.
So India can of course restart migration
oil. No question about it. Black Panther
says will the US have any cards to play
in the war? The US has all kinds of
cards to play but the cards won't work.
That's the problem.
They are not going to be able to defeat
Iran. It'll take a long long long time
to defeat Iran.
So they'll use various cards. They may
even use the nuclear option possibly,
especially if Iran takes out an aircraft
carrier or something or if Israel comes
under tremendous pressure. The Americans
may consider that. But they have all
kinds of cards. They have cards that I
will not even discuss here because
Okay. Handuranga says if you were what
if you were Iran's next supreme leader.
See Iran's supreme leader has to be
first of all a Muslim and secondly a
Shia and then he has to be a very great
scholar in Islamic law and Shia things
and what what not. I am eminently
unqualified from all perspectives. So I
can't be Iran's next supreme leader.
[laughter]
Sergeant Skylan says can we massproduce
drones and missiles like Iran? weaken
mass-produced drones and missiles way
more than Iran.
Iran is doing this under so many
constraints. It has been hit with every
sanction you can imagine. It has been
cut off economically from the rest of
the world. Iran doesn't have the kind of
resources India has. India can
massproduce drones and missiles way more
than Iran. And you know what? It will
boost India's economy. If we set up
drone and missile manufacturing plants,
it will give employment to tens of
thousands, hundreds of thousands of
people,
of course, we can do it, but we choose
not to do any of these things.
Prataradana says, "Alegedly, next
targets are Turkey and Saudis. Will
Arabs change course and distance
themselves from the US, make peace with
Iran? Also, I saw one missile versus 11
Israeli interceptors."
Yeah, I've also seen that sort of thing.
All these Iron Dome interceptors going
up and the missile just dodging them and
coming down.
And these Iranian missiles are releasing
u releasing a burst releasing a cluster
of decoys. Each decoy glows like a like
the exhaust of the missile. So each
decoy mimics a missile and that totally
confuses the interceptor missiles. And
they're like, "What do I hit now?" And
then the
u the kill vehicle which contains the
warhead that then acquires hypersonic
velocity just slams down. Yeah. So
that's what uh allegedly next targets
are Turkey and Saudis. Um will will
Arabs change course and distance
themselves from the US? They would love
to. Now now they've realized the US are
not the US had no intention of saving
them.
And uh but can they can they ask the US
to leave? Pack up your bags and leave
leave our territory, dismantle your
military locations. Will they be able to
do that? I don't think so. I mean,
recently Spain said to to Trump that we
will not allow the US to use Spanish uh
ports for your operations. Trump said,
first of all, I'm going to cut off all
economic ties with Spain, and secondly,
I'm going to use your ports whether you
like it or not.
because I'm strong enough to do that and
there's nothing you can do about it.
That's pure blackmail and arm twisting
right Trump. So they can he can do that
to the Arabs too. So we'll see about
whether the next Turkey targets are
Turkey and Saudis but yeah we'll see.
Sh says what's the situation in Tel Aiv
as of now I think Twitter has now
censored whatever is coming out of Tel
Aiv in Israel. We are not getting any
any fresh information anymore. Twitter
was supposed to be the place where you
get the latest information right in real
time. Not happening now. Um I suspect
the situation in Tel Aiv is pretty
pretty dire.
The videos that came out in the past 3
days or something, they showed all kinds
of missiles slamming into Tel Aviv all
over the place. I mean entire
neighborhoods turned into rubble. So Tel
Aiv seems to be in in bad shape right
now. Yeah.
Vidi Manar says what's our way out of
all this? Can we change stand?
uh we can change stands anytime we want
but it will it will bring a set each
stand has a set of circumstances so I
think prime minister Modi has taken the
best and most practical possible stand
right now based on ground realities and
and being practical rather than rather
than based on ideology
um
can we change the stand
we can I suppose see what what's our way
out of all this see right We are not
dragged into the conflict. The Americans
will want us to be dragged into the
conflict. We we should ideally say no. I
don't know if Mr. Modi will be able to
say no to the to Trump if he asks for
Indian ports, but ideally we should say
no and we should stay out of the matter.
That way we will be out of it. We should
ensure that we don't get dragged into it
and we should watch what's happening
observe very in great detail what's
happening and whatever military lessons
and strategic tactical lessons we can
learn we should learn them and very
rapidly implement them. So like I said
we need a stockpile of hundreds of
thousands of drones and tens of
thousands of missiles of various kinds.
Do we have it? We don't have it. So
start doing it. That's what we should
do.
Ashish Kumar says India picked a side
but stayed neutral in Russia Ukraine.
Why the different stance? What does this
mean for bricks? If India fights
Pakistan, will West Asia support it? And
who actually backs Iran in this
conflict? Is it alone?
Okay, you you ask me every possible
question here which is fine which is
fine. Who backs Iran in this conflict?
Is it alone? It's fighting alone. Who's
who's fighting with it? It's fighting
it's fighting alone. Um it has backing
from Russia and China. Russia and China
are providing uh Iran uh an alternative
to the GPS system. Obviously, America's
GPS is not available in in to Iran and
to the Iranian military. So, Iran is
using the Russian uh GLONAS in the
Chinese BU and China is also apparently
supplying Iran with satellite imagery of
the battle space so that they know
exactly what's happening. So, that's the
kind of support Iran has indirect
support, not direct support. If India
fights Pakistan, will West Asia support
India?
Well, Iran would have supported India.
The Arab nations would won't support
India.
Uh India picked aside here because we
had no choice. Trump would have forced
us behind the scenes. Arm twisting. Uh
we stayed Russia neutral in Russia and
Ukraine. Yeah, our stand was different.
Now it has changed. The past 6 months
something has changed. Operation
Synindur was our last great resistance.
After that we have kind of buckled. Why
the different stance? The different
stance is because of the leverage
Americans have applied on India. What
does it mean for bricks? We'll see about
that. Bricks doesn't seem to be a very
actively
viable organization right now too much.
Fields strong man says you mentioned
that America is less likely to send a
warship to hormones because of getting
shot by missiles. So what with what
confidence? Trump tweets that he will
send send ships to escort oil tankers.
Bluff card. Trump
is known to lie on on an ongoing daily
basis.
Last year during after the 12-day war
with Iran, he bombed Natans and Ferdo,
right? The US aircraft bombed bombed the
Iranian facilities of Natans and Fdo
nuclear facilities. And then Trump
declared that Iran Iran's nuclear
program has been destroyed forever.
Trump declared that last year that
America has permanently destroyed Iran's
nuclear program.
Today he is saying that we are fighting
this war against Iran so that Iran does
not become a nuclear power. Which means
that he was either lying at that time or
he is lying right now. Trump lies on an
ongoing daily basis. He's a liar.
I hope I have established that he has
been lying.
Right? So if Trump has tweeted that they
will send ships, he's lying.
Trump also said that we have unlimited
supplies of arms and ammunition
missiles. He's lying. He lies on a daily
ongoing basis. Okay.
Air is mantic horses. I think India
probably foresaw the situation as
possibility. We have pretty good raw
experts in Iran and Israel. India is
reacting very calibratedly to the
situation. I doesn't seem too surprised.
Okay. So if India foresaw the situation
and that this war would happen, why does
India only have a stockpile of about 25
days of oil if we foraw this? That's a
that's a question that's
relevant and valid. I think
swastik chunker says we have significant
and historic Shia population in India.
Shia fought with us against Patans in
16th century. Also Shia and Hindus ruled
together also husb
seems government has chosen sides. The
government of India has chosen sides
based on practical considerations not
ideology or religion
and I'm not aware of this the history of
the Shia people I'm not really
IPK1 says we might see East India
Company 2.0 zero before GTA 6. GTA 6
Grand Theft Auto. Okay. I am not a
gamer, so I don't know about that. But
okay. Okay. One hopes not. One hopes
not.
Blue Saka says, "In the last few
podcasts, you said that Iran is not
going to last in the war. Then why are
you changing his stance now?" Did I say
that that Iran won't last in the war?
I am not sure if I would have said that
but so I don't remember but
Iran won't last long.
Okay. But see even if I may have said
that you can always reassess the
situation
based on what's happening and what you
are seeing and then you can give a
better more informed interpretation of
what's happening. Right? You can do
that. It is it is perfectly
um okay
to change your stance based on what's
happening in the world with when more
information becomes available.
If I make a statement 6 months ago, does
it mean that it is set in stone and I
can never change my stance or never
change my views or never change my
perspective?
Kakashi says if we sell out and
vasalize, can we develop like the like
the UAE?
Look at the situation in the UAE today.
Let's say hypothetically they're sold
out and vasalized.
Look at the situation.
They are going backwards now. Their
entire economic model is gone.
and see to to develop like the see okay
I I I know what you mean if you in case
some of you have gone to the UAE the UAE
is like a much better version of India
you it's full of Indians but it's like
India if all the corruption was gone and
everything was done right
that's the kind of nation the UAE is all
the roads are like first world country
roads nobody breaks traffic rules
everybody follows the laws and law and
order there is no crime time
the living standards are very high. So
it's like if we if you do India right
that's what you get. You get the UAE.
So if we sell out in saladalas will be
we will become like the UAE. No because
in India the the standards are very low.
The system the UA system is different.
India system is different. The system
won't change here. So India will remain
a mediocre nation even if it vasalizes.
Pavan Kumar KM says looks like Chinese
HQ9 has failed again. Pakistan,
Venezuela, now Iran. World may move
towards India for Akash or Russia which
is best proven defense.
Even the Iron Dome has failed.
Iran is pummeling Tel Aviv in other
cities. So the Iron Dome has failed. The
American Patriot system has failed.
Their terminal high altitude area
defense system THAD has failed.
Their $1.1 billion dollar radar has been
destroyed by the Iranians.
Everything has failed. So why only
single out the Chinese,
right?
Everything has failed.
Every air defense system has limitations
and the limitations are essentially
mathematical.
Will the world move towards India for
Akash?
Um, don't know. Or Russia, the Americans
won't allow the world to buy Russian
weapons. India will have to, India has
no option to do it because it's good,
but most nations won't be allowed by the
Americans to buy Russian systems.
Rakin Khan says, "What made Iraq lose in
2003 and Iran sustain resist the US in
2026? if you could just lay out the
difference between their defense system
strategy if relevant. Good, good, good,
great question. Great, great, great.
Why did Iraq lose in 2003?
And why is Iran able to resist in 2026,
23 years later? Iran is been being able
to resist the Americans today and give a
mur job like you say because Iran has a
stockpile of maybe more than one lakh
drones and maybe more than 10,000
ballistic missiles. That is a gigantic
stockpile.
Because of this stockpile they can keep
fighting for months
and they can outlast their enemies. the
American and Israeli stockpiles of of
interceptor missiles will run out very
soon and cruise missiles and whatnot.
Everything Iran has been preparing for
46 years for this war. Iraq in 2003 was
under American sanctions just like Iraq
Iran but Iraq did not build up this kind
of stockpile of drones, missiles,
whatever. They did not have the
defenses. So that's why they were wiped
out very soon and the Americans
essentially flattened Iraq. They
flattened Baghdad. They flattened TikT.
They flattened everything and then they
walked in.
They can't do it in Iran because Iran is
just too powerful. Why is it too
powerful? Because it has worked very
hard to build up these stock piles. Iraq
did not do that and that's why they
lost. That's the main core issue.
Kajor Bithorn says fighting a losing war
against Afghanistan helping the US
against Iran ignoring the murder of its
own civilians. Pakistan's biggest worry
India's buildup at no times on the
border. Weird. Are we going to strike
while Uncle Sam is busy or would that be
stupid? See idea. See right the
situation is that Pakistan is fighting a
war against Afghanistan. The situation
right now is war. I I'll show you. Wait,
if we go to a Google
um Afghanistan Pakistan war 2026,
even Wikipedia recognizes what's going
on right now as a war. So Pakistan is
right now embroiled in a war with
Afghanistan.
The Pakistanis, they launched air
strikes on Afghan civilians and killed a
bunch of Afghan civilians around 21 or
something February. And less than a week
later, the Afghans retaliated by by
launching attacks across the border, the
the disputed border Duran line and they
captured a bunch of Pakistani military
outposts and the war has been going on
since then.
So Pakistan has this big issue with
Afghanistan. There's an active war with
Afghanistan.
Apparently Pakistani territory is being
used by Americans, American aircraft to
to to transit Pakistani territory and
launch possibly operations against Iran.
Maybe the Americans may also be quietly
operating an air base or two in
Pakistani territory. So the Pakistanis
are complicit and involved in the
American operations against Iran. Let's
be clear about that. So on the one hand
on Pakistan's western border there's the
Iran war. In the northern border there's
the Afghan war. Okay. And then there are
no times that is India is issuing now.
Uh so
is it a good time for India to strike in
Pakistan while Uncle Sam is busy? Well,
actually if you
consider the whole situation, this is
the ideal time for India to destroy
Pakistan. The terrorist nation. America
has said that it's fighting Iran because
Iran is a terrorist nation, right? But
Pakistan is an actual proven terrorist
nation. We can use the American logic
and apply it to Pakistan right now. and
Pakistan already is embroiled in
Afghanistan and Iran also in some way.
This is the right time to go after
Pakistan and balkconize Pakistan and our
Afghan brothers and sisters will welcome
that and they will they will also
participate in this. This is the right
time actually. But do you think Uncle
Sam is blind? Do you think Uncle Sam has
only two eyes and he was only looking at
Iran? Uncle Sam has 20,000 eyes.
They have a bunch of people who are only
looking at the subcontinent and they've
got a bunch of people who know that this
is a good time for India to strike at
Pakistan.
So will the Americans allow India to do
this?
I mean they can't stop India from doing
it. But the last time a war happened
3-day war the Americans came and stopped
India right?
So if India goes starts operation Sindur
again now we have to make sure that the
Americans can't stop us. So it has to be
very rapid. Whatever military objectives
we have, we should we should achieve
those in in 48 to 72 hours. It can't be
3 days we'll do air drone warfare, then
air force, then something else. No,
finish it off in 3 days.
But America will not like it obviously
because Pakistan is a very valuable
asset for them. So India will have to
face consequences. But if India does
want to do it, this is the right time.
There's no other better time than this.
Vihung Quran says with India choosing US
and Israel's side in the war how will it
affect our relationship with Russia and
China? Can it make China more hostile
towards us in the near future? Thank you
for such a detailed analysis. Okay,
thank you. Um see India has chosen the
side of the US and Israel in this war
verbally verbally
we haven't actually taken any action
against Iran. We have given verbal
support to Israel and the US and the
various Gulf nations and we have chosen
not to uh convey our condolences to the
people of Iran over the assassination of
their supreme leader. We have kept quiet
about that. So yeah it it will you can
say that it it means India has chosen
one side but India has chosen the side
verbally not materially not through
actions. Um so that won't affect our
relationship with Russia and China?
Not really. It it it the optics aren't
great but it doesn't really affect the
relationship with Russia and China. What
can affect our relationship with Russia
is if India stops buying Russian oil
which allegedly India has kind of
definitely cut down on Russian oil in
the past few months. So that can affect
India's relationship with Russia because
its actions. We were buying a lot of oil
from Russia and we were obviously paying
Russia for it. So it was helping Russia
and it was helping us. Now if we cut
down significantly drastically the
purchase of Russian oil that obviously
is going to strain the India Russian
relationship and now that Hormos is
closed we are going back to Russia
or maybe it was all pre-planned. I don't
know I don't know. So that sort of thing
can strain a relationship. Uh China
India and China look the the
relationship isn't normal anyway. The
relationship isn't friendly
and China has always been hostile to
India. So we don't care if China gets
more more hostile or not because we have
taken some decision somewhere. China can
go and mind its own business.
If China was a friendly nation, we would
have considered China's feelings about
this matter. But China is is a hostile
nation. China is a nation that has for
decades refused to demarcate the India
Tibet border, which is a hostile act.
So I don't care what China thinks or
whether China's precious little feelings
are hurt
and anyway we have the means to defend
ourselves from China if if need be. So
it doesn't matter. Russia is important.
China I don't care.
Black Panther says which one best India
non-alignment or multi alignment.
Multi-alignment is always best not
non-alignment. Non-alignment is stupid.
Multi-alignment makes a lot of sense.
Okay.
Mukt says to trust anything and any
report of US at the moment is foolish.
Give at least 5 days to confirm and
never believe the reports and stories on
their arsenal and realtime war assets
propaganda warfare promax. I completely
agree. The only nation that can be
trusted is India. So when there's a
clash with China and 20 Indian soldiers
die, India reports immediately 20
soldiers died.
China lost probably 80 90 soldiers but
even today they're claiming it's only
four who died. But India
says we have to speak the truth.
The only nation that gives genuine
accurate analysis wartime reporting of
its losses is India which I think is
It's mental retardation.
The Americans probably have lost
hundreds of soldiers but they are saying
they've lost only six. That is what a
self-respecting
and and intelligent nation does.
Aries Mantor says, "Luckily, we did not
sign a mutual defense agreement with the
UAE, otherwise we would have been
dragged into this war immediately. It's
a sign that we haven't vosalized yet to
the US. Lemoa will be abused her here."
Or the Americans will try and leverage
Limoa. Apparently, Limoa is not it's not
mandatory that we give access to our
ports to the Americans, but they will
try and arm twist the hell out of us for
sure.
Um yeah, we don't have a mutual defense
agreement with the UAE and because of
that we don't have to be involved in the
war which well turns out it's a good
thing. Yeah.
Uh says but sir I believe that Mossad is
the best and is best one and win. Okay
sir. Okay.
Putin says could taco become the brv or
gorbacha of the US? Well, taco will be
the taco of the US. He will have his own
special characteristics which are
different from those of Brv in Gurbach.
Gorbachev was a sellout.
Gorbachev essentially essentially was a
traitor.
He presided over the final destruction
of the USSR. He essentially was a US
agent. Taco is nobody's agent. Maybe
he's he was an agent of Epstein or
something. [laughter]
BRJV. So Taco is taco. You can't compare
him with Brnav or Gurbachev.
Hajor Horn says if we have only 30 days
of oil and the rich Gulf countries are
going to run out of food will Pakistan,
Afghanistan and others river to the
stone age in a few weeks.
We have about 25 days of oil apparently.
But we will hopefully get resume buying
large quantities of oil from Russia.
Maybe we can ask the Americans for oil.
They will sell it at three times the
market rate or whatever. But we will
somehow get the oil. But it's going to
cause hardship in India. And then the
politicians will lecture you. Stop using
air conditioners, stop doing this, stop
doing that, stop watching TV, stop stop
using fans,
be frugal while they live in the 100 cr
bungalows and all. That's what they will
do. Um so India will manage. Gulf
countries are going to run out of food
possibly if this drags on for a few
weeks. The Gulf countries are going to
be in deep deep trouble. Not just food,
water also. So will Pakistan,
Afghanistan and others revert to the
stone age in a few weeks? uh not the
stone age but it's going to be terrible
hardship if this goes on for weeks or
months there's going to be significant
hardships Pakistan Afghanistan are not
affected the Gulf countries are affected
Pakistan obviously needs oil it doesn't
have its own oil so it will also be
affected from the because of the oil
shortage Afghanistan also so everybody's
going to be affected in in a variety of
different ways unique ways
Goautam says can't the US dock their
ships in Karach then they have a lot of
ships
and one port can't accommodate them all
and I'm not sure Karachi can handle a
lot a lot of ships
so that's that's the problem
that is the problem
man says don't be surprised by Indians
having eccentric views during this war
we have 1.4 4 billion people garbage and
gems are easy to find at scale. India is
ordered chaos incarnate nation first.
Nation first of course and yeah yeah
yeah it's okay Indians have all all
kinds of views many extent views as well
that's okay that's okay I'm not
surprised
Buddha goes nuclear says Finnish
president in India is that significant
something about Ukraine or Russian oil
or anything else I have not even looked
at this matter at all I am aware the
Finnish president was in India today I
am aware of that because I saw Mr. Modi
tweet about something. Beyond that, I
have not looked into it. I have no idea
what the agenda is.
Finland
member of NATO of course. So I have not
looked into this right now. My entire
focus is on what's happening west of the
west coast of India, the Gulf region.
That's what I'm looking at. Uh I'll I'll
look into this but right now I don't
have an answer for you unfortunately.
Sorry.
Anaman Singh says US can't exit the Iran
war because of its imperial hubris.
Question mark. No. See Trump
has ordered this gigantic military
buildup in West Asia around Iran. This
military buildup has happened over the
last 2 three months, couple of months.
The Americans flew hundreds of cargo
plane sorties from America into these
military bases in West Asia. They have
sent a whole bunch of ships there.
They've sent a whole lot of material, a
whole lot of people there, soldiers.
This entire set of activities would have
cost them billions of dollars and months
of time. So they have fully invested
their time, effort, energy, money,
everything into building up this
military buildup.
Then Trump has ordered the attack on
Iran. So the attack is happening. So
after investing so much money
and starting a war,
if you then say, "Oh, it's not working
out. We'll move out." It is a
humiliation
for the United States and personally for
Trump and that will destroy Trump's
political standing. The American midterm
elections are due in November or
something this year. The Republican
party will be wiped out of existence in
the in the midterms. That is the
existential crisis Trump is facing and
that's why he can't exit Iran. He has to
somehow find a way to win. How do you
win now? He'll have to invent a victory
out of something. Maybe he'll have to
use some special weapons. I don't know.
That's the deal.
Spider-Man says, "Following your channel
for past 5 years, five plus years. Best
ever, sir." Thank you so much, sir.
Thank you so much. I really appreciate
that. Thank you, sir. Or Spider-Man,
sir. [laughter]
Thank you. Priyankeshmuk says, "What
might happen in the next few years if
India does show resilience against US
demands?"
while India will grow a spine
and for a few years things may be tough
for India the Americans will apply
pressure and they will make it hard for
India's India to grow economically but
if you if India can somehow show
resilience for the next 5 years and keep
going growing its economy at 6 7% per
year in about 5 years India will be at a
at a stage where it will be hard for the
Americans to keep pressurizing us Right?
So if India does not cave in, if India
shows resilience until let's say 2030 31
by that time it will become impossible
for anybody to to arm twist India.
So the next five years are critical.
They're crucial. The next 5 years are a
make or break time for India.
Shas Jada says 4.3 magnitude earthquake
on the recctor scale doesn't indicate
nukes. So there was a ma there was an
earthquake in some part of Iran which
was 4.3 on the RTER scale and I went
okay let's let's find out together shall
we let's see how this analysis has done
was there an earthquake in Iran recently
4.3 magnitude RT scale
okay this happened on Tuesday so today
is Wednesday so this happened yesterday
uh Girash far province
Gash Paris Province
Province
Earthquake.
Right. Do we have any seismological
data?
Seismological data.
Do we have any of that volcano
discovery?
Logical whatever news on air IR
let's see March 3, 2026.
So we have this earthquake that
happened. How deep was the earthquake?
What was the depth? The depth was 10
kilometers.
Do you see my dear viewers? The depth
was 10 kilometers.
The earthquake originated 10 kilometers
below the earth's surface. Now let's do
another search.
Deepest hole ever dug.
Cola super deep bore hole 12 km. So the
deepest hole ever dug which took years
to dig was 12 km deep. Do you think Iran
will dig a hole 10 km deep to test a
nuclear weapon? No. Nobody has the time
to do that. It'll take years. So this
earthquake happened at at a depth of
about 10 kilometers, which means it's a
natural earthquake. It's not a nuclear
test. And a nuclear test doesn't
generate a 4.3 magnitude magnitude
earthquake. Probably less than that. So
it's not a nuclear test. All right.
Black Panther says, explain Iranian
versus Persian difference. Who owns the
land?
See, Iran is this new name of the land.
The old see who are the Persian people?
Their original name was the Parhua
people.
They were the people who who used the
paru in warfare. The Paru means the
battle axe in Sanskrit. Paru.
And maybe they were warriors who
preferred to use the paru in warfare.
That's why they were called the Parua
people. And they settled in this land
west of India outside after leaving
India.
And because they settled in the land,
the land eventually got a name based on
their name. So they were the Parha
people. And this land eventually came to
be known as the as Porsche.
And their capital was Parapur which the
Greeks called Persipalolis. It's today
called Para in in Iran. So historically
the land was Persia,
named after the people, the Paro people,
the Persians.
Later in the 20th century, it was
renamed to Iran. Uh the land of the
Aryans
by that guy Bahavi. No difference who
owns the land. The Persian people on on
the land. The Persian people are the
true natives of the land.
Aris Manticor says this situation is
engineered by the USA. Trump said he
forced Israel. Is he doing this to cause
a sharp spike in oil prices to sell
Venezuelan oil for immense profit and
integrates it fast into the oil economy?
I don't know this entire business is
about
gaining control of the world's oil
resources.
It's not about manipulating the market
and causing sharp spikes and all that.
It's about taking control of all the oil
reserves in the world, major oil
reserves. By doing that, you are
targeting China. The objective is to is
to
control
the sources of China's energy so that
you can then arm twist China on demand.
That's the whole
that's the whole point of whatever the
Americans are doing. It may look very
random. One day Venezuela, another day
um Iran, third day Ecuador. Ecuador is
different but Venezuela Iran is all
about oil. Okay.
Chinmai says, "Will India hit Iran and
yes, how which weapons if dragged into
war. Given Iran was a kind of an ally
kind of helping us before the war,
Afghanistan, Armenia,
India will not hit Iran. It will be
incredibly absurdly stupid if India hits
Iran. If yes, which weapons, I am not
even discussing which weapons because
India should never do that.
India should not get involved in this
war against Iran. India should not do
anything that is detrimental to Iran
and the Americans will ask for access to
Indian ports. India should deny that
also.
Uh India should not get dragged into
this war no matter what happens. I hope
so. But we I don't know what constraints
the government of India is facing so I
can't say but India should not hit Iran
whatsoever in any way whatsoever.
Hyphen says, "I'm still optimistic India
will get out get out of the situation
and keep rising. Also, I hope people
realize how bad any war is. These days,
people talk about war like it's
something to be proud of." I agree with
you. Wars are horrible things.
It's true that nations sometimes need to
go to war. Sometimes there are just
causes for war and a lot of you can
achieve a lot of your geopolitical
objectives only through war. So war is
is well it's it's a fact of life
geopolitically. If you look at human
history all major geopolitical change
has happened through warfare only. But
the fact is that wars are the wars are
the wars cause immense suffering
to civilians to non-combatants.
They cause immense humanitarian
suffering.
It's all nice on the TV screen when you
watch movies and all but if you actually
have to face the consequences of warfare
they are horrible. They're horrific.
Right? So wars are bad and I you know we
should avoid war as far as possible. So
I agree with you about that completely
and I'm also optimistic that India will
keep rising and India will find a way to
to to find its way. So I am optimistic.
We should all remain optimistic. All
right.
PP5K1
says did US took hard hit back? US
commander motivating soldiers saying
Jesus will return the war. Senator
saying the situation is worse than
expected. The US underestimated Iran's
missile power. You are right to be
worried. The US has taken very hard hits
and they are not revealing that right
now. Okay.
their uh their their
fifth fleet which is based in Bahrain
that entire infrastructure seems to have
been destroyed or damaged significantly.
Uh one of their billion dollar radars
was destroyed.
The Iranians have hit at least one
American ship.
The Iranians have uh hit various hotels
in which lots of American personnel were
stay staying and they have hit specific
floors and specific rooms
and the Iranians are hitting Israel very
hard. They're hitting American allies
very hard. So the Americans are taking
big big hits. They're not confessing
that to the world. They're not admitting
that because in war you don't say these
things. You keep it quiet. But the
situation for the US is much worse than
what they had ever expected. It's been a
shock for the US. And yeah, there was
some things, some mention of Jesus or
whatever. I didn't look into that. But
yeah, some mention of Jesus coming back
or something.
Aristot says, "I fully believe and trust
your frustrations about fellow Indians
supporting us, Israel or Iran in this
war. The education system must face
severe recelling for producing such
billion such brilliance."
Yeah. Well,
it's just a fact of life in India,
right? It's just a fact in India that
the education system produces people who
can't can't understand the world
properly. So, it's not their fault and
one must also not get too frustrated
about this. So, it is what it is.
Anyway, thank you sir. Thank you very
much. Ang Singh says Deutschand or
France dominant power if US exits
Europe? None of them. If the US exits
Europe, what do you think will happen?
One nation will emerge as a dominant
power. No. The moment the Americans exit
Europe, the Europeans go back to the
tribal warfare and they go to war and
they they will be back at each other's
throats. No dominant power right now.
Long-term it could be either Deutsland
or France or England perhaps. Maybe
England's time is gone now. We'll see.
Maybe Poland.
Sager Gare says, "What about Indians who
bought property in Gulf countries? Was
it? Why is is infrastructure enough?
Without strong defense and security,
without strong defense and security,
nothing is enough and your investments
are they could go down the drain. So
those Indians who have bought property
in the Gulf, I think
you know
it it may turn out it will probably turn
out to not be a very wise decision.
I don't we all know there are lots of
Indians who have bought property in the
Gulf countries. Lots of Indians, wealthy
Indians live in Dubai because it's just
a couple of hours away from India. You
can come back to India anytime you feel
like. You can take a flight today
morning, tomorrow morning and come to
India if you want. So that's why the
Gulf region is so u
it's it's so convenient for wealthy
people. But if the situation continues
and these Gulf cities become unviable
as long-term residences, all those
properties their prices will plummet.
and uh those investments will be wasted
to a certain extent at least. Was this
wise? Well, was it wise of the Gulf
nations to trust the American promise
that we will support, we will take care
of your security and defense? It wasn't
wise. So, this all happens because you
trusted the American military umbrella
and security umbrella. Was it wise? In
hindsight, probably it wasn't wise.
Gotham says, "Just for fun, it looks
like US is going to lose its sovereignty
first in your list. [laughter]
Based on what Marco Rubio has said,
looks like they have lost their
sovereignty already." Yeah. I mean,
Israel dragged dragged Trump into the
war.
Dol Johan says, "What are the scenarios
of India getting into this war?"
How could India get into the war? India
will not get involved directly but India
may be forced to give access to Indian
to American warships give American
warships access to Indian bases so that
in that way India is kind of indirectly
involved in the war beyond that I don't
think anything else will happen
Spider-Man says good evening sir in your
live stream you said power and might
prevails over morality in geopolitics
does this mean that nations must seek
power by any means does it also apply to
person's lives
Okay, first question. Does it mean that
nations must seek power power by any
means? Absolutely yes.
You can't play the game by a different
set of rules compared to the others. If
everybody is seeking power by any means,
you have no choice but to seek power by
any means or be left behind and become a
victim. So yes, nations must seek power
by any means. Learn from the US. Does
this also apply in people's lives? No.
people's see all the rules of
geopolitics also apply in your personal
life but in your personal life it's not
like you acquire power and get weapons
and stuff right so the rules apply
differently in the depending on the
context in people's lives but yes if you
are able to acquire power
well it's beneficial for you it doesn't
mean that you should acquire power
anyhow by being unethical or whatever
that's a personal choice at the end of
the day it depends on your personal
ethics but I would say don't acquire it
by any means but If you are a nation,
you have to acquire it by any means
whatsoever like the Americans do. Anan
Singh says, "Will India replace China in
selling Iranian oil?"
And I don't see that happening.
India doesn't sell Iran. China also
doesn't sell Iranian oil. You mean
buying or selling?
Um I don't know.
Resish says can Oman be used against
instead of the straight of Hormuz?
You can't have ships coming through
through Oman, right? Oman is is on land.
See where is map?
Let us bring map on screen. Yes.
Right. Okay. So, we're talking about
Oman.
So Oman is this large nation, reasonably
large nation in in in the western in in
the eastern part of the Arabian
Peninsula. So if you want to bypass the
state of Hormus, can those those tankers
and ships come through Oman? But Oman is
land ships can only pass through sea. So
it's not possible. If you want to bring
oil through Oman, you will have to build
construct pipelines which takes years.
So not practical. You see, it's not
practical.
Ashish says why can't US use Pakistani
ports instead of dragging India because
they want to put India under pressure.
Pakistan only has one or two ports Chaba
not Chabar sorry so Guadada and Karachi
and Guadada is very close to Iran. If
the Americans use Guadada, Iranians can
take it out immediately.
The Iranians can wipe Guadar out of the
face of the earth. And if the Americans
aren Karachi, the Iranians can attack
Karachi, too. Let's look at the map.
Karachi isn't that far from Iran, right?
I mean, even India is not that far. But
see, Karachi is here. How far is Karachi
from, let's say, some part of Iran? 600
km. Very easy to target Karachi. Very
easy.
So, the Americans will want to operate
at a reasonable distance from Iran,
which makes Indian ports ideal. You see
that's why Aris Mantor says I think
India should produce millions of DRNS
and thousands DRNS and thousand tens of
thousands of Brahos as a national
mission no matter the situation. Jind
YouTube censoring my words used a lot of
euphemisms here. DRNS.
Okay.
DRNS. Drones. Wait a minute. Drones are
millions.
I would say drones hundreds of
thousands. Maybe a million also is good.
Yeah,
we should do that. We should do that. We
should have at least 10,000 ballistic
missiles, maybe another 10,000 cruise
missiles depending on our threat
perception and so on. And obviously, I
would say way more drones. India should
do that. India should wake the wake the
hell up.
Until now, India looks like it's been
dozing, sleeping. India needs to wake
the hell up.
And I agree we should do this as a
national mission. Absolutely.
Okay. Answer says vau Iranians are
celebrating seems wrong for some reason.
Well, in any nation you will have some
people who are woke, some people who are
antiational, some people who are this,
some people that it's going to happen in
every nation and they will do what they
do. You can't control them, right? Yeah.
If it seems to wrong to you, well, maybe
it seems right to them. People are
different, right? So it's okay. Romit
Mishra says, "I was in delusion
regarding India's situation on on a
geopolitical level. Watching your
streams really gave the real picture
about the world. You're doing great
work." Thank you very much, sir. I'm
glad that my streams have helped you in
some way. Thank you very much for your
very kind words.
Thank you.
Ritik Yadu Ritik Yadu says, "Will
Pakistan also join in to attack Iran?"
>> [clears throat]
>> I think Pakistan has been given a
different task. Pakistan's job from the
American perspective is to assist them
in the operations of Nidan. Maybe by
allowing American aircraft to fly over
Pakistani territory and maybe use
Pakistani one or two Pakistani airports
that much they will use Pakistan for. I
don't think the Americans want to use
Pakistan to attack Iran because in the
eastern part of Iran it's mostly desert,
right? There's not not not a lot of
cities or whatever to attack. See if you
look at Iran, let's go to the map.
If you look at Iran, the major cities
and all are all in the west of Iran near
Pakistan. It's all desert, desert,
desert. Thousand kilometers of desert
obviously you have, see, look at this
uh
bandas, it's it's far from Pakistan.
You you have Zahedan, but there's not
not much to attack over there. That's
why the Americans will not use Pakistan
for that that purpose. They will use
Pakistan uh for the purpose of maybe
doing warfs and all that and monitoring
Iran situation from the east. Pakistan's
real utility for the US is as a
counterweight to India and as a nuisance
towards India. That's the real purpose
of Pakistan. So Pakistan will not
probably probably not join in the attack
to Iran against Iran.
Global says Trump said this. Spain said
we can't use their bases. We could use
their bases if you want. We could just
fly in and use it. No one's going to
tell us not to use it. Yeah. Trump said
that. Trump said, see, Spain said that
told the US, you can't use our our bases
for your war against Iran.
So, Spain has denied America the
permission to use their bases. So, Trump
said, "I don't care.
I don't care. We're going to use it and
there's nothing Spain can do about it."
That's what Trump said. Might is right
in geopolitics. Okay.
The US is just way too powerful. There's
nothing Spain can do. If the Americans
decide to use the bases, if the
Spaniards try to try to forcibly evict
the Americans, the Americans will invade
Spain tomorrow morning. They can't do
that. And Spain can't defend itself the
way Iran defends itself. Spain is
helpless. So
Fashion Rice says closing up to the US,
terrible idea. Well, history tells you
it's a terrible idea. History will tell
you it's a terrible idea.
Sedarth Gal says, "What lessons can
India learn from this current
situation?" I think I answered that.
India needs to stockpile very large
quantities of drones, ballistic
missiles, cruise missiles,
augment our military infrastructure
and so much more. So yeah, these are the
lessons straight away we can learn from
the current situation.
Datani says this is my told you so
moment that Donald Trump has taken Iran
lightly. Do you think that Senate may
Trump uh [clears throat]
do you think the Senate may throw him
under the bus exit the war?
Um yeah, Donald Trump has taken Iran
lightly. I agree. I agree with you. Uh
can the Senate end the war? I don't
think the Senate can end the war. the
the president the the supreme commander
u I think they can't in what way will
they throw him under the bus I'm not
sure uh I am not sure what the legal uh
methods are of let's say throwing a
president under the bus I'm not sure how
it works and I'm not sure if the Senate
has
the ability to stop a war if it's going
on I'm not sure if it's a possibility
but yes he has definitely taken Iran
lightly Yeah, feels strong man says
super slam equal to punch. I was making
a joke about how Hexath said they were
there to strike first because [snorts]
Iran will strike in the future after
Israel strikes them. Lol. Okay. Okay.
Got it. Got it. Super slam means punch.
Yay. Okay. Arian Sharma says,
"What is the epic Brihhat Kata and what
remains of it in the modern date and how
was it destroyed? I have absolutely no
idea. I don't know what this is. Brihhat
kata. Let me quickly do a Google search.
But I am not aware of this. But let me
see. Do I find something?
Brihhat kata. Brihhat kata. What is
that? The great darcient Indian epic.
Oh, in pesachi. Oh.
So when was this composed?
It existed in the 6th century AD. But we
don't know when it was exactly written.
And it is written in Pishachi. Well,
well, well, well, well.
The Pishachas used to speak this
language. The demons. Okay. So, yeah, I
am not aware of this. I have not studied
the history of this text. I'm not sure
about it, but it's fascinating that it's
written in the extinct language called
Pesachi.
I'm not sure what remains of it. We'll
have to read it up. So, yeah.
Gibb says, "Your prediction for the
winner of the Iran versus America war.
If Iran is not destroyed, it wins. Iran
is fighting for what? Survival. Trump is
fighting for the destruction of Iran and
regime change and what whatever else.
So, whoever achieves their objectives is
the winner. For Iran, the objective is
to survive. If Iran survives, it's the
winner and Trump loses. My prediction is
that Iran wins.
Aris Manticor says fault lines are so
many are too many, but solutions are
being done slowly at ground level. too
much CIA and traitors will face constant
sabotage and sabotage for any oath
actions. It will show in decades
unfortunately. Well, there are certain
endeavors that take decades and these
endeavors are still very worthwhile. If
we can let's say
solve these problems in the next 50
years, it is it's it's a worthwhile time
frame to solve issues.
So yeah, let us be patient and let's
work towards it.
Nirish Pula thank you very much sir
thank you
Datani says USL what would that prevent
bulcanization no it will accelerate
bulcanization
the US doesn't reward its vasals with
nice things the US rewards its vasals
with destruction in different ways Japan
is an American vasal they have rewarded
Japan in the past 30 years with the
destruction of their economy and the
destruction of the total fertility rate
In a 100 years, we don't even know if
Japanese people will still exist.
And for a nation like India, they will
want to balconize it. Becoming a US
facile will not prevent balconization.
It will accelerate bulcanization.
Nirish Polla, thank you very much, sir
once again. Thank you, sir.
Hardik Jooshi says, "How is this war
even making sense for America or Israel?
I failed to see the conviction behind
the claimed reasons. If you were to
assess the nuances, how can this really
turn out both good and bad?" See,
no nation will say that we are going to
destroy a civilization of 90 million
people because we want their oil.
Okay? No nation will say that. So they
will say, "No, we are doing this because
Iran is a terrorist nation and uh we
want to demilitarize Iran and we want to
make sure they don't have any more
missiles and we want to make sure they
don't have a nuclear program." All these
long excuses they'll give, but the real
reason is they want to destroy Iran so
that they can take the oil.
Okay, that's why they're doing it. Why
would why do they want to take the oil
to pressure China more? So for the
long-term geopolitical game of
pressuring China, they want to destroy
this nation. That's the truth. But you
can't say that openly, right? That's why
you come up with all these excuses.
That's the American perspective.
Israel's perspective is Iran says that
Israel has no right to exist. That's why
Iran sees Iran as as an existential
threat and that's why Israel wants to
destroy Iran. Well, from their
perspective, they are right, I suppose.
So that these are the real reasons. You
have to understand that certain things
are not stated. You have to understand
what is not stated. The unstated things
are actually more important than what
people say.
How can this really turn out both good
or bad? We'll see. We'll see. It looks
like Iran will survive this and the
Americans will not succeed in destroying
them and Israelis also.
102 etc. says, "Will the Middle East
construction
construction market pick up again as
this will impact lots of jobs involved?
What are your thoughts?" Nah,
this war is going to go on for months.
While missiles and drones are flying, no
construction will happen. Nothing.
And this and in case the US is not able
to destroy Iran or defeat Iran then this
tense situation will go on for years
beyond any ceasefire.
Um so I think construction is not going
to pick up anytime soon in the next few
months or next couple of years and yeah
it will impact a lot of jobs involved.
Yes it will. Now who's to blame for
this? Blame Iran. No, Iran didn't start
this
right. That is the unfortunate reality.
Unfortunately,
Manticor says, "Apologies for differing
opinion, but I believe India is
pragmatic. We have aligned here, not
chosen a side completely. There is a
more subtle strategy to protect
remaining sovereignty. It looks like
submission, but it's not. See, like I
said, India has chosen a side for
practical reasons, not for ideological
reasons.
Practical reasons means we are being
pragmatic.
We are trying our best to protect
whatever sovereignty we have left,
right? We have aligned so that we don't
come under immediate attack or whatever.
So I think Mr. Modi is doing the best he
can given the options he has and the
constraint he faces. I think he's doing
a great job. I am by no means
criticizing Mr. Modi. I think he's
taking India in the best possible
direction considering the constraints
and circumstances.
Sometimes you have to temporarily
pretend like you're bending the knee.
That also is a thing in geopolitics,
right? So I think India is being
pragmatic and I don't think you have a
differing opinion there.
I'm not saying India has vasalized
itself as of now at least. We have
chosen a side but like I said earlier we
have chosen a side verbally. We have not
taken actions
in that direction like we have not
joined the attack on Iran. We are not
supporting any action against Iran. We
have just verbally supported Israel and
the US and so on.
Banak says sir France Deutsland
Vij
enter in Iran and by this Russia China
enter World War II. We'll see about
that. It looks like the Americans are
pressurizing various European countries
to get involved in the war. Okay. Maybe
France, maybe Germany, maybe England,
maybe somebody else. So, if that
happens, if more European nations join
in and pile in on on Iran, then Russia
will definitely be tempted to get
involved on Iran's behalf because Russia
and China can't afford to see Iran being
destroyed. Iran is too important. And if
this sort of thing happens, it's the
beginning of World War II actually.
Omnag says in a global situation like
this how to get reliable information as
there are as some are biased propaganda
and does US obsession with Israel cause
of Jews role in building the US in a
global situation how to get reliable
information very difficult we have to
look at lots of different sources so
until yesterday there was good
information on Twitter but now it's gone
now something has changed Elon Musk has
changed some algorithm to hide what's
happening apparently so then what do you
Well, there is Telegram, but then in
Telegram, you have to find the right
channels. Then there are all the
propaganda outlets like BBC, CNN, etc.,
which will only give you lies, which
will only give you one side of the
story. So, ideally, if there's a
situation like this, you want to see
both sides. You want to see what Iran is
saying and claiming. You want to see
what the US and Israel are saying and
claiming. So, it's difficult, but you
have to try your best. Uh, is the US
obsession with Israel because of Jews
role in building the US? No, it's
because of Jews being very influential
today in in US politics and very
powerful.
MK says, "Can nuclear armed drones and
UUVs exist like nuclear artillery? Can
Iran destroy ICE completely if Iran has
no option left?" ICE Israel.
Ah, okay.
Um, can nuclear armed drones and what's
a UUV? Let me quickly take a look at
what is a UUV.
Um, UUV,
unmanned underwater vehicles.
Um,
can nuclear armed drones exist? Yes. Can
UUVs, nuclear UVs exist? Yes. Uh, what
is that
super cavitating torpedo? Let me see.
Okay.
Russian super cavitating torpedo.
What's it called? I forgot. Ah, squal.
So, this is a this is a supersonic.
No, it's not supersonic, but it's a
super cavitating dropppy though. And it
can carry nuclear warheads. So, it's
essentially an underwater UV, right?
Isn't it? And other kinds of UUVs can
also carry nuclear weapons. Yes. So, it
can. Yeah, it's definitely these can
definitely exist. Can Iran destroy
Israel completely if Iran has no option
left?
It depends on how much
how many ballistic missiles and drones
Iran still has left. If Iran still has a
few thousand left, it can certainly
unload them all on on Israel. So it
depends on the circumstances. How far
how deep are we in the war? How many
months has it been and so on? Depends.
But then Iran but then Israel also has
options like nuclear weapons. Hope
Abishek Shivasav says Kalug at is at
peak only Mahadev can save us. Well well
I call upon Mahadev to save us. Yes
Mahadev.
Okay.
Rain has become a new member. Thank you
very much. Rain welcome to the
membership of the channel. Thank you
very much. Madavara has become a member.
Thank you very much sir. Welcome to the
channel's membership.
PK political says no matter how many
aijits bash India in the mask of RW
Barat will become Vishuru and Vixit.
Okay, this is a criticism towards me.
All right sir.
Yes that's that's I'll be the happiest
if Bat becomes Vishwaguru in Vikas. I
hope so. Yes.
Me Patel says could this be a ploy by
the US to increase the demand of
Venezuelan oil? No it is not that.
may stretch it out until crude prices
skyrocket and say all objectives
achieved.
No, this is not about increasing demand
of Venezuelan oil. Venezuela doesn't
have the capacity to turn out a lot of
oil. Venezuela has infrastructure
constraints. It has probably 20% of the
cralable oil reserves. But the
Venezuelan oil is heavy sour crude oil.
It's thick and heavy and full of sulfur.
Very high sulfur content. There's only
two or three refineries in the entire
world that can refine that oil. One is
in India. So even if you increase the
the production of Venezuelan oil, how it
there's a bottleneck which is the number
of refineries. So this is nothing to do
with Venezuela. Okay? It has nothing to
do with Venezuela. It's all about
constraining. It's all about the
American objective of of of controlling
Iran's oil
oil fields.
Vehav says, "What in your opinion does
India need to do to protect itself from
being bulcanized? What about the
interior front of the two and a half
front war?" Look,
the first thing India needs to do is to
evict all foreigners who are illegally
squatting on Indian territory.
I don't know how many millions of
Bangladeshes we have in India today.
Illegal infiltrators. What is preventing
the government of India from deporting
them all? Aren't they a massive national
security threat? Then the the godamn how
many lacks of cookies and whatnot in
Manipur who have come from Burma in the
last few years
all foreigners. Why can't they be
deported? Why can't all the Rohingyas be
deported who are squatting on Indian
territory when operation tandur happened
they they discovered tens of thousands
of Pakistanis who have been living in
India. What is India a joke or what?
That's just one thing India needs to do.
There are so many other things
right
there are these there are billions of
dollars flowing into India every year
for the purpose of carrying out
industrial scale religious conversions.
Why is India allowing this to happen?
Has India no self-respect?
There's so many things India needs to
do.
Okay. Rahun Rajar says why not use cargo
planes for oil. Arun
[laughter]
there are issues with carrying large
volumes of liquid
liquid tends to slosh around. Slosh
slosh sllosh if you're in an aircraft
and the liquid starts slloshing for some
reason it will affect the stability of
the aircraft.
That's one issue. The second thing is
that if you want to have oil on a cargo
plane, the oil is very heavy,
very heavy. Cargo planes probably can't
take that only a certain amount of oil
which doesn't make it cost effective. So
there are issues, many issues like that.
Ritik says, "How would you rate Kami as
compared to Palavi?" Palavi was a
foreign puppet who sold his nation for a
few dollars.
Kame did not do that. That's the
difference. Kakashi says you said we've
picked a side but after Iran, India is
next. Why would US come for us if you
have already chosen the side?
[laughter]
Because their long-term objective for
India is balconization.
If India has chosen a side and we said
that okay we are on your side. Does it
mean that they will not they will give
up their long-term objectives?
Their long-term objective is to
bulcanize India. Their long-term
objective is to ensure India does not
become in the next 2025 years a new
China.
So for that they have to ensure India
remains mediocre. India remains a four 5
trillion economy and the best way to
achieve that is to break India apart. So
even if you pick their side they're
going to go after you when the time
comes.
Okay.
V4 says not in my name not my PM. I'm
not sure what you're talking about, but
all right, sir. Aris Manteor says India
has already started placing mass orders
for Russian oil numbers that will make
Trump and Bessant scream tariff, tariff,
tariff. Outstanding. Let it bring it on.
It's fine. Good. Ah Shar says, "What are
the chances that India rise from all
that's happening and avoid a avoid a
split?"
um India rises from what's happening and
avoids a split. I think avoiding a split
is is not that hard but it will be tough
for India not to become a American vasal
in the next 5 years. So I've been I've
said this many times that it is there
there are there's a significant
possibility that India will become a US
vasal in the next 5 years. Um it's also
possible we don't go down that road if
we show strong leadership and we show
the ability to withstand some temporary
pain. So I think the chances are there
that India will be able to rise from all
of this and avoid being split and all
that. I think the chances are decent. So
let's all be optimistic and work towards
that.
Spandon
Spandon Nahar says your views on HPV
vaccine drive. Should we take it because
Bill and Meinda Gates foundation is
involved? Do you think government could
be complicit for money? Uh I don't know
if the government see I haven't studied
this vaccine. I've heard all kinds of
nasty things about Bill and Binda Gates
their foundation and I've heard all
kinds of nasty things about their
vaccine experiments in India
and my question is why do girls need to
take the HPV vaccine?
What does it prevent human papilloma
virus? Okay, let's let's quickly Google
this. Okay?
What is a HPV vaccine?
Uh highly it's I don't I'm not asking
you if it's highly effective or safe.
Okay. Human papillo papillo virus. It
prevents cancers in general that stuff.
Uh boys and girls. Okay. To prevent
cancer causing infections.
Okay. What is this human papilloma
virus?
Uh intimate skin-to-skin contact.
Okay. Highly contagious common virus.
Who gets this? You get it only through
intimate skin-to-skin contact. Now that
obviously means sexual intercourse or
something like that. Now
this will only come through sexual
promos promiscuity and that sort of
behavior. Now why do we want to assume
that all girls will behave like that? So
I think there is something fishy behind
this. I'm not sure what it is. I have
not researched in detail but my point is
we should avoid unnecessary
vaccinations.
Too many vaccinations isn't good.
But I so that's my overall stance on
vaccinations as a whole. Some
vaccinations obviously are very
beneficial but some may be unnecessary.
I'm not sure why this we suddenly need
this new vaccine when there is no
epidemic of human papilloma virus in
India. Why do we need this now? I'm not
sure. I'm not sure. I'm kind of
skeptical about this. Nage says as of
today ideal short-term investment one
year oil, gold, silver or whole cash. I
have no idea. I am not an investment
expert. Sorry.
EA
more than 10k says please do holy stream
with subscribers from next year. Lots of
love from PM Modi Nuji. [laughter]
Okay. From next year. Thank you. Thank
you. All right. Thank you for the
recommendation.
Saga Singh Parer says, "Now that we are
being dragged into a war, should we also
take actions to achieve our tasks, our
goals? Take back PK and X and liberate
Baljasthan."
Look, we have not yet been dragged into
the war. Okay.
the Americans I promise you are going to
try and force India to give their
warships access to our ports.
If we let's I I will my recommendation
is India should say no no matter what
happens but let's say because of various
reasons we can't say no in that case we
should put conditions okay you want
access to my ports you allow me to take
P and break Pakistan into three pieces
in if you allow me to do that then I'll
give you give you access to my ports so
we have to negotiate and negotiate
really hard
so yeah it could be an opportunity to do
that perhaps
Sumish Pandya says Europe versus Turkey
after Iran versus US and Israel. Uh, who
knows? Who knows? Turkey is the black
sheep in NATO. So, it's possible
perhaps.
QTX says, "Can't deep state injured
Trump just to avoid nuclear stage with
Iran? Nuclear war is worse for
everyone." Well, the deep state will do
what deep state wants. If the deep state
thinks that the that a nuclear war is
bad, then it'll just tell Trump to shut
the shut the hell to to sit the hell
down. That's it. That's all they have to
do. So they don't they don't have to
scare him or injure him or whatever.
They just have to tell him sit down and
that's done.
Joy, thank you very much, sir.
Rajiv Rana is a new member. Thank you
very much, sir. Welcome to the channel's
membership. Thank you.
Black Panther says if US operating
through empire or deep state how is the
Mr. taco playing with without proper
strategy changing the decision is the
deep state weak
I think
the see Trump hasn't made a un
unilateral decision he would have asked
the US military for an assessment for
various plans plan A plan B plan C how
to best best take down Iran and so on
and based on their recommendations and
their plans and their projections he
would have given the go-ahehead for a
strike in the in the beginning of the
war against Iran So it means Trump isn't
incompetent. His mil military has messed
up.
His military, the US military doctrine
is outdated.
Okay,
that's the problem. They can bring in
massive air power and flatten cities,
but their objective is a regime change
and maybe then
and then their actual objective is to
take control of the oil of Iran. So
their warfighting doctrine is is a
totally different kind of doctrine. It
it is not modern in the sense that it
doesn't it can't factor in what Iran is
doing. Tens of tens of maybe 10,000
missiles and 100,000 drones the sort of
thing. It can't deal with that. So it's
not entirely Trump's fault to a large
extent it's the US military's fault.
Anikit says yes Indian education system
has so many issues but calling Iranian
system better which TC's death to
non-believers is not right okay sir
thank you hit thank you very much sir
thank you
Kuruketra says waiting for raising
standard series all right sir all right
okay Vikana says Iris dinina incident
has taken to Hindu Twitter people are
very angry it's become
It has become an emotional thing. Guest
issue people calling Indian Ocean claim
bluff. Okay, let us see what's happening
on uh Twitter.
Twitter
let us see
uh give me a second. Let's put Twitter
on the screen.
Okay.
Um Masoud Peskan. What's he talking
about? Let's quickly see. Masoud Pes
Peskan.
Dear esteemed leaders of our friendly
and neighboring countries, we have
strived with your assistance into
diplomacy to avoid war. However, the
American Zionist military attack has
left us with no choice but to defend
ourselves. We respect your sovereignty
and still believe that the region's
peace must be insured. Okay, nice. Fine.
That's fine. Um, Qatar Qatar is shutting
down the world's largest LG export
plant. Would you believe it? Uh, but we
talking about uh
Dina, right? D E Nina
Mercumi.
Okay, thank you. That's fine.
The sailors.
Okay.
Right, right, right, right, right,
right.
Okay. Okay. So, there's going to be a
lot of soulsearching and yeah emotions
over here because of what the Americans
have done to this Iranian ship in what
we call our backyard. Okay.
Air is manticor says apologies again.
Operation Sundur was a wakeup call for
India to the current US strategy. We
will act close but retaliate fiercely
and pragmatically when our red lines are
crossed. We are firmer now but more open
to flexible strategies. Well, I hope
that you are entirely 100% right. Okay.
All right. All right. Yeah.
Uh
Swap. Swap Nant. Thank you very much.
Swapnant G. Thank you. Prahua. Thank you
very much. Prauma G. Thank you sir.
Black Panther says East India Company
filed bankruptcy. Karma.
Okay. I don't know but okay. If it's the
case karma. [laughter]
Adik says why people here are fredding
spreading fake news that India stopped
buying Russian oil but truth is in
February they purchased 6% more oil from
then than earlier months they are still
largest suppliers of crude oil in
February to India okay let's let's let's
debunk all the nonsense let's see here
right u
okay how much crude oil did India
purchase from Russia in the last 3
months
So it's
we still purchasing I suppose what does
the Hindu have to say 44 month low in
January. So yeah there are ups and downs
but we haven't stopped the purchases of
Russian oil.
Um
yeah so we haven't stopped buying
Russian oil.
It's gone up and down and so on and uh
Trump obviously had see the reason is
this reason is this understand this when
India agreed to this uh interim
framework for a trade agreement with the
US
Trump added some extra conditions that
the US would be monitoring India and he
said that I'm bringing the tariffs down
on the condition that India stops
purchasing Russian oil in India he said
and he claimed that India had committed
that it will stop purchasing Russian oil
and then the imports of Russian oil did
go down significantly. So that's the
situation. I don't think we have stopped
completely. Now we're going to buy more
again because we have no choice. Mr.
Henlow says apparently Qatar is going to
shut fully shut LG production
temporarily. Trump is also saying the US
will export tankers through hormones if
we have only 25 days of oil. We are in a
fix. So Qatar is going to temporarily
completely fully shut its LG production
because of the circumstances. Trump is
saying the US will escort tankers
through hormones. He's lying. It's not
possible. It will not work. And we
apparently have only 25 days of oil,
strategic reserves, which is a joke, but
I don't know why it's like that, but
whatever. So we are in a fix. Yes, we
are in a fix. So we will have to
purchase way more oil from Russia now.
and maybe look for other uh sources also
which probably means that Trump will
impose another 25% tariffs on us but it
is what it is. Yeah.
Aris Mandicor says regarding India
foreseeing the situation we have 56 days
of strategic reserves we very quickly
reach a deal with Russia suspiciously
suspiciously.
Maybe there is some strategic foresight
at work over here perhaps or some see
the report I saw yesterday in various
media outlets was 25 days of reserves.
Now some people are saying that's not
true. It's 56 days. Some people are
saying it's 74 days. Whatever.
Why don't we have 365 days of strategic
reserves? That's my point.
That's my point.
Reddi always ready says does India even
have current offensive capabilities of
Iran? No, it does not.
Iran has perhaps 10,000 ballistic
missiles. Iran has more than a 100,000
drones. India doesn't have anything like
that number of drones. India doesn't
have anything like that number of
missiles, ballistic missiles. We may
have invested in maybe large numbers of
cruise missiles, maybe a few thousand
cruise missiles, Brahos etc. But not
ballistic missiles. So India has been
sleeping all this time. Not entirely
sleeping. We can definitely give what
they say m job jab to Pakistan but we
should be militarily so prepared that
everyone around us trembles when they
think about us that's how it should be
right so yeah that that's an issue
black panther says US pull Pakistan
troops into Iran war to fight behalf US
I don't know about that
u if if things go badly they may ask
Pakistan to do that that as
Anerud Kumar says, "What's US's greatest
weakness this era or year?" I think one
issue is leadership. They have poor
leadership. Secondly, their military
doctrine is outdated and they have this
sense of hubris that nobody
that that we can we can defeat everybody
and no one is a match for us. These seem
to be some of their weaknesses. Um yeah,
market whisperer says, "What if IR after
a few weeks, Iran after a few weeks
declare that they now have nuclear
warheads and will take the Samson option
if pushed? How do you think the US is
and Israel will react?
The US and Israel and the whole world
will remain skeptical about Iranian
claims. If Iran says that we have
nuclear warheads but if Iran tests one
nuclear weapon
then the world will not be skeptical.
The world will take it very seriously.
So Iran if we if it wants to go down
this road it has to test at least one
nuclear weapon. It has to test it. Maybe
atmospheric test, maybe underground
test, whatever. It has to test it
in such a way that the whole world
notices and then you declare that now if
you cross certain lines we will use a
samson option then the world will take
it seriously.
Rohan bid says American ships are on our
west coast in February American
officials visited our western command
was the visit a hint that we agreed to
take part in the war
I'm not sure.
I'm not sure. I'm not even sure who
approved this goddamn visit of these
American
officials to our western command.
That was that was wrong in my opinion.
Very wrong.
So does it indicate or does it serve as
a hint that we have agreed to take part
in this war? I'm not sure. I don't think
uh in if something happened in February,
it means that we have agreed to take
part in a war that happens in March. I'm
not 100% sure about that. I think it's
unlikely. Perhaps at the time India
would have known that the war is coming
but we would not have known exactly when
the war will happen
and even if we knew it's coming
we aren't taking part in the war right
now. So I think that's that's kind of
unlikely.
Konu says we live in Dubai. Should we
stay or leave? Do you what do you
suggest looking at the current
situation? Please advise will the
situation escalate in the Middle East?
Look, if the war continues longer,
the situation could escalate. I don't
think the Iranians will target civilians
anywhere.
They have targeted some hotels in the
UAE. They have targeted hotels where
they had intelligence that American
soldiers or officials were staying. So
that's that's why they took out some
floors and some rooms in certain hotels.
Apart from that they have targeted
strategic infrastructure like oil
production facilities, um desalinization
facilities, uh American military bases
and so on. They have not gone after
civilians.
So if you're living in Dubai and you are
not close to any strategic installation,
you will be safe.
But the problem is that eventually
Dubai will run out of food and water.
Then what do you do?
That is a very strong possibility.
Hormones is closed. 80% of Dubai's food
comes through hormones.
Wait 2 weeks, there will be a food
shortage. And if the situation persists
and if Iran takes out some desalination
plants in the UE, then you will start
facing water shortages. So that is what
could happen. I'm not saying it's
guaranteed to happen, but it's a
possibility.
Okay, it's a possibility. And this war
is not ending anytime soon. I hope it
does, but it seems unlikely. It seems
like it will go on for weeks, months,
maybe years.
And if if this situation slowly becomes
bad for Iran, they will hit harder
at at various American assets and
strategic assets. So that is the
situation overall. So based on whatever
I I can see that's what I can tell you
and based on what I say and your own
assessment of the risks and all that
because you live there you know things
better you need to make your own
decision.
Yeah that's what I can tell you. Uh your
decision has to be your own. I have told
you the risk assessment that I see the
scenarios that I see. So you need to
make your own decision based on that.
Not just what I say but what others are
also saying. You have to look beyond me.
Maybe I'm wrong. It's possible that I'm
not entirely right. Maybe some other
analysts or whoever is there, they may
give you a better perspective. I don't
know. So, you know, don't look at only
one person. Look at lots of different
take a 360°ree perspective and use your
own experience and and uh uh your own
perspective in in in consider consider
that too because you are a resident. You
know better. Based on all of that, you
need to make a decision. Yeah.
So, all the best, sir. All the best.
Konchu.
But Jimna says, "What will happen to the
Middle East power balance? The US has
not been able to protect its vasals and
since [snorts] Iran is going all out."
Good question. See, in 2003, the whole
power balance in in Middle East was
changed by the Americans when they
destroyed Iraq, when they vasalized
Iraq. Today Iraq is not a power.
Iraq's power score is zero. Hard power
score is zero. Today the Americans took
it out completely. So in 2003 they
completely altered the power balance.
Now in 2026 we have a certain kind of
power balance in West Asia. We have Iran
as a major power and then you have all
the American puppets who are all
cumulatively kind of balancing Iran out
and the Americans have un been able to
protect their ass. Of course, we also
have Israel, which is which is a more
powerful nation than Iran. So, we have
the situation. What will happen? It
depends on the events of the war. If the
Americans somehow succeed in defeating
Iran, then the entire balance of power
changes and Iran and Israel becomes the
most dominant power in the region. But
if Iran cannot be defeated,
then the power balance kind of remains
the way it is. But if Iran is weakened,
then other powers get slightly better,
you know, relative strength and so on.
Um yeah,
here is Manticor says the US of US army
officer using Christian prophecies to
justify war to soldiers is both absurd
and ironic yet suspicious to SCOP likely
do you think? I don't know. Um
a scop against whom? Against their own
people, against their own army, against
somebody else I don't know. Strange in
my opinion
strange. I I fail to understand what's
the purpose of this
Christian professor to to justify the
war to its soldiers. A lot of soldiers
may not be Christian, right? Many people
in the US are atheists now. So I don't
know what the what the purpose of this
thing is. If it's a scop, it's a scop
against whom? That's what I'm wondering.
Don't know this love. Thank you very
much, sir.
He is manticor says the spine can bend
but not break. This is an advanced
strategy that we are playing that even
China chose to ignore because of hubris
5 years first and 50 next. One hope so
five years first but stand the next 5
years be resilient the next 5 years and
then
grow the next 50 years. One hope so yes
sir let's be optimistic.
Anul Jen says Turkey got hit by Iran.
Will article 5 get activated? Has it got
hit by Iran?
Turkey Iran.
Let's see. Iran's first strike on NATO
member.
Um Iran fires missile at Turkey
destroyed by NATO air defense.
Okay. So Turkey has not been hit but
they are claiming that there was an
missile fired at Turkey which was
intercepted and destroyed. So that will
not yet trigger article 5. But uh let's
wait and watch. Let's keep an eye on
this. This seems to be an evolving
situation. Iran targeting Turkey. I'll
have to double check that. Okay.
Shashir, thank you very much, sir.
Ammon Kumar Dankar says, "Classified AI
war game scenarios of US not optical
optimal."
Classified AI war game scenarios of US
not optimal.
Well, AI is also built on assumptions.
Yeah, looks like they've messed up
somewhere. even their their AI wargaming
has not worked out for them clearly
because in any AI wargaming scenario or
situation you have to give some inputs
those inputs typically are based on
assumptions you make so even the AI
starts if it starts with wrong
assumptions it'll give you wrong outputs
yeah anik says if Iran hits
carrier it will be fun and open eyes of
Indian leadership by the way we 50 days
oil in reserve and We can't dig oil
reserve tunnel overnight. See, you can't
dig oil reserve tunnels overnight. But
if you have 12 years to do the work, you
can do it. My question is why in the
past 10 15 years have we not build build
up oil reserves that will last us 365
days or even 2 years? Were we sleeping?
That's my point.
Today, let's say we have 25 days of
reserves, maybe 50 days of reserves. Why
don't we have 3 years of reserves?
We can't we do it over over 10 15 years.
Why don't we have this? That's my point.
That is my point. That's why fr That's
what annoys and frustrates me so much
that there is no strategic foresight.
Iran knew this war is coming. They have
been preparing for 45 46 years. So could
India not do something? at least build
up some more strategic reserves and
store oil. I just don't get it.
Uh career and all. We'll see about that.
This love says what happened in the
Indian Ocean. What happened in the
Indian Ocean is that near the coast of
Sri Lanka, there was this Iran Iranian
warship that was passing by. The Iranian
warship was earlier a few days ago in
India participating in a naval exercise
with with our navy. And once the
exercise got over, it was going back to
Iran. It was south of Sri Lanka, very
close to Sri Lanka. And over there, it
was torpedoed by an American submarine.
It was destroyed and more than 100
sailors are missing. So that's what's
happened in the Indian Ocean.
AU says how CIA failed to analyze Iran's
contingency plans. The CIA's job is not
to analyze the nation's contingency
plans. The CIA's job is to forment
problems in nations. It's the US
intelligence services and who military
intelligence etc whose job is to do all
these things and looks like they made
very bad assumptions and they have been
caught completely by surprise and
they've been shocked by what's happened.
Clearly they did not anticipate what
Iran will be capable of doing. Clearly
they have failed miserably in
anticipating what will happen. I don't
know how but yeah
V says what's your opinion on the
declassification of alien files by Trump
do you think that we have alien
technology used in modern military
warfare I doubt it very very much I am
pretty sure aliens exist
okay the universe is vast universe the
observable universe is about 10 raised
to 23 stars that is one with 23 zeros
behind it that's how many stars you have
Even if one each star has only one
planet you have 10 to 23 planets.
If one out of a million planets planets
can have life. Then you have 10 to 17
planets that have some form of life.
Maybe microbial life or whatever. If one
out of a million of that have
intelligent life, you have 10 to 11
planets with intelligent life.
Intelligent life means us. So that is a
tremendous number of planets, right? So
I am pretty sure aliens exist out there
but the universe is mostly empty. It's
too vast and I think I think it's very
unlikely that they have visited us and
given us a their technology. Right? So
I'm very very very skeptical about this
thing. I will be the happiest person if
we find out that aliens are here and
they visited us but I think it's very
unlikely and this declassification of
alien fights by Trump and all. I think
it's just a waste of time. Maybe they're
trying to divert people's attention away
into something useless to hide something
else.
Abhinav says Abhinav says how can the US
mess up so badly? How come they did not
plan a plan B? Is the US empire in
decline? By the way, Indian air defenses
sales go
clearly their plan A was a disaster. I
don't know how they have messed up so
badly, but they have messed up. I think
they will have a plan B and a plan C. I
think the plan B will be to take the war
long and try to bulcanize Iran by arbing
various ethnic groups and all that. So
that will be their plan B. So they they
are very good at these things but that
takes time and the Iranians will not
allow just sit sit sit and watch. So the
Americans their initial assumption seems
to have been like we will win the war in
two days. By the by the time the weekend
is over, Iran will have been defeated or
they may have come begging come to us
begging us to negotiate.
That didn't work. So clearly they made
wrong assumptions and they messed up
very badly. How did they mess up very
badly? I'm not sure. That's classified I
suppose.
Dark Side of the Moon says, "Why did you
why did the [clears throat] US start the
war with Iran knowing it harms Gulf
economies?
Does it mean Jewish interests outweigh
Arab petro dollar capital sustaining US
markets?
It looks like the US did not start the
war at all. Looks like the Israelis
started the war and the US seem to have
some kind of obligation that if Israel
is in any kind of danger, they have to
step in
because Marco Rubio, the Secretary of
State said very clearly that we
we started the war because we knew that
somebody's going to attack Iran and if
Iran is attacked by someone, they will
attack us too. So that's why we attack
first after somebody else attack. Who is
it? Somebody else obviously is Israel.
We know that Israel attacked first. So
the US did not start the war. The
Israelis started the war. The Israelis
don't care about the Gulf economies.
Even the US doesn't care about the Gulf
economies. Uh so that's the thing.
That's that's what's actually happened.
So Schneer says, can we buy SEO without
declaring it in the media or to the
world or or to the US whichever company
works on this has to keep everything
confidential.
Technically I suppose we can do it. Um
but it'll be very hard to hide these
things because production lines are
massive
and there are too many people involved
in this
and the the word typically comes out. So
we can try I suppose we can do it
quietly but typically these things are
almost impossible to hide.
Prattab VGM says why some Indians are
behaving like Israel is dad. I think
there's a there there's a tendency of a
lot of Indians to hero worship certain
nations right full support s why do they
do it because see it's not their fault
because the education system doesn't
given them has robbed them of the
ability to think critically that's why
the hero worship some countries and they
idolize some countries
yeah
shir G says why didn't the CIA or Bossad
know about the missiles I don't know I
don't know I think They they based their
assumptions based on what happened in
the 12-day war last year in which Isra
did launch basiles and do some damage
but it was not extensive it was not
massive
right so maybe they and maybe they
believed that they had already that that
they would be able to achieve complete
air supremacy over Iran and we've
already destroyed natans and furough so
you know Iran is just it needs it just
needs one more blow before it is
destroyed maybe that's what they assume
assumed clearly Their assumptions were
terribly terribly off target off the
mark.
Anchul Gupta says the US sank Iranian
ship near Sri Lanka India's backyard.
What will India do? Where's foreign
policy headed next 5 years? Five things
India is doing right.
What will India do about this? India
will do absolutely nothing about this.
Absolutely nothing. This happened
outside of India. This happened outside
of India's territorial waters. So, India
will do absolutely nothing about this.
Where is the foreign policy headed over
the next five years? We'll have to see,
sir. We'll have to see. Five things
India is doing right. I don't know.
Five things India is doing right. Uh
I don't know.
Yeah, we are buying Russian oil again.
That's one thing we are doing, right? We
buying S400. That's another thing we
doing, right? I'm sure there are more
things. I'm sure there are more things.
Akash Badra, thank you very much sir.
Thank you very much.
Pratipar Roy says New Zealand defeated
South Africa scored 12 173 in 12.5
overs. Finn Allen of 33. Good god they
are into the finals. Hopefully against
India on Sunday. South Africa is out of
the tournament. Well, thank you for the
update. Oh, the match was going on. Was
it right now? Yeah. All right, maybe
I'll see the highlights maybe tomorrow
or whatever. Anyway, thank you sir for
the updates and uh update and I hope
that India wins the semi-final right
whenever it happens. Tomorrow is it
maybe tomorrow. Okay.
Dark first says in what circumstances
should we fear Pakistan
in the current circumstance? We should
fear them because they're a terrorist
nation, right? As long as they are a
terrorist nation, they they are to be
feared because they have this propensity
to target civilians. So we should fear
them.
Our Rajun Rajar says is Pakistan's job
to assist in securing Bram.
Uh perhaps
perhaps the US does seek Bram. Bagram is
a very very strategically important air
base, vital air base. The US definitely
does seek to repossess it and maybe they
could perhaps use Pakistan as a tool in
making this happen. So yeah, it's
possible.
Alex George asks a very interesting and
relevant question. Why does the United
Nations seem inactive in conflicts such
as the Iran war and the situation in
Venezuela? Because the United Nations is
obsolete, outdated, and youthless and
worthless. The UN does nothing today. It
simply serves as a tool of the powerful
nations that make up the UN, but it
doesn't really have any actual
beneficial impact on the world. When was
the last time the UN did anything of any
any worth anything worthwhile? It's been
decades. I suppose the UN is inactive.
The UN is uninvolved in peace. Let me
show you the meme. Okay.
United Nations uninvolved in peace.
Check this out.
This
is
what the UN actually is. It's uninvolved
in peace.
The UN is obsolete, useless, worthless.
It should be disbanded.
Rohan says, "Will the Russians join or
leave Iran alone in this war?" It'll all
depend on how the war goes. Right now,
Iran is able to fight on its own.
But if Iran finds itself in a situation
where it has to be rescued then Russia
may step in and rescue Iran.
Pratep Kumar voices CIA is preparing
Kuresh invasion of Iran. Yes, Trump has
made some statements about this and the
CIA may be working on this matter and
they will make this will make the Turks
extremely unhappy and displeased because
Turkey will oppose this tooth and nail.
But yeah, Tommy Versati says, "Why are
Russia and China not backing Iran?" See,
Iran is very accurately targeting
various targets through its ballistic
missiles and through its drones. How is
Iran getting the locations, specific
exact locations? Because the Americans
who own GPS would have switched off GPS
for Iran. So, the Iranian military can't
use GPS. Now what the Iranian military
is doing it's using Glonas which is
Russian and BU which is Chinese. So the
Russian and Chinese alternatives to GPS
Iran is using that. Secondly the Chinese
are giving Iran apparently high quality
high resolution satellite imagery in re
almost real time so that Iran knows
exactly what's happening. So Russia and
China are indirectly
helping Iran right now. Iran is able to
fight on its own. In the future if there
is a situation when Iran needs help most
likely Russia at least will step in.
Okay. Jri Jri Vishatan says
he
know
Shanti Mahabharat.
All right. So you are saying this is sit
obviously
um so you saying that dharma and shaky
go together right essentially that's
what that's what this shloka means
okay so essentially the the distilled
meaning is that without without shi
there is no dharma You need to maintain
structure if you want to if you want to
preserve dharma more or less. Right.
Right. Agree.
Struggler says Poland is seeking nukes
apparently. I think Poland has made a
statement that they will now look
towards becoming a nuclear nuclear
weapon state. Yeah, the world is getting
more interesting now, isn't it?
Pratipar Royce's 50,000 troops
participate in US operation against
Iran. Israel invades southern Lebanon.
Yeah. Well, you see this is called
escalation.
This escalation. 50,000 troops are
participating in the American operation.
Well, how about putting troops on the
ground? Boots on the ground, Uncle Sam.
We'll see about that.
W says, "Russia and Ukraine fighting in
Europe and USI, Israel, and Iran
involved in a war. Do you think China
might see an opportunity to take
Taiwan?" Absolutely not. China will not
try to take Taiwan at this point in
time. No, it'll be disaster for China.
Uh first of all, the straight of
foremost is closed and the oil that
China gets from that place that region
about 30 to 40% of China's oil it's now
stopped. China obviously has strategic
oil reserves but China will not you know
use this do try invasion at this time at
this point in time and secondly
the US is way too powerful in China's
own backyard and right now the US has
hundreds of military bases in the region
and China doesn't have the appetite for
risk China doesn't want to risk any
damage or destruction of its industrial
infrastructure so I I think this is not
the right time for China to even
consider making a move on Taiwan.
Spider-Man says you said Dharma will
disappear in next 50 years max. Why? I
didn't say Max. I didn't say Max. I said
it's possible that Dharma may not last
50 or 100 years. Why? Because of the
situation.
I explained in great detail when I said
see you remember I said this will
happen, right? So why don't you remember
why I said it will happen? I explained
why this could happen. I didn't
guarantee it will disappear in 50 years.
I said every new generation is getting
progressively deassinated. There's
industrial scale demographic
engineer re-engineering happening in
India. Industrial scale conversions to
other religions. So many issues I've
listed out.
Why don't you remember that sir
Spider-Man I said that you remember what
I said but you don't don't remember the
reasons I gave.
So I have not said it will disappear in
50 years max. is not what I said. I said
it could disappear in 100 years, maybe
even in 50 years. I didn't say it'll
disappear in 50 50 years max. That is
not right.
Rohan says, "What are your views on
China arming Iran? The mysterious 25
cargo planes landing in Iran with
transponders off. Clearly, China has uh
supplied something to Iran and something
in reasonably large quantities, right?
25 cargo planes. Uh that's what one even
I've heard. So I don't know what China
supplied to Iran. Was it arms? Was it
ammunition? Was it something else? I
don't know. But clearly the Chinese did
supply something. So you can say that
China and Russia are both indirectly
assisting Iran in some way or the other.
But the fighting and all of that is
being done by Iran. So I don't I have no
other views beyond that because I don't
know what was supplied to Iran. But
clearly something of use probably
something of military use.
House of Discussion says, "Is Iran's
death Israel's trap? Iran dies. Who's
next?"
Um, does No, I don't see it that way.
No. No.
Adita
says USA controls Israel or Israel
controls USA. From what we have seen the
past 3, four, five days, Israel dragged
America into this war.
And once Israel started the war, America
had no option but to join. So from that
you can maybe surmize that Israel
controls the USA.
Okay. Chira Chiag Raj says order of
things change education system remove
reserve reservation.
I think changing the education system
will take 20 30 years.
Why do I say this? Because we have seen
how China has transformed their
education system. It took about 30 plus
years for China to do that.
That's a very long process but it has to
be done. But res removing reservations
is just a signature on a piece of paper.
Right? So that can be done first. That
can be done first. So first remove the
reservations or change the way
reservations are done.
Instead of making reservations cast,
make them based on a family's financial
status, financial condition.
So those who genuinely need
reservations, they'll they'll get it and
do it only for maybe 10 20 years and
then remove it completely. So that's
what needs to be done. Modern samurai
gaming says, "How are you so genius? How
can one become like you?" I have no
idea. I don't think I'm a genius. I'm
just interested in certain things and I
speak about those things. I don't think
I'm a genius. How can you become like
me?
Don't try to become like me. Be you. Be
the best version of yourself. You have I
guarantee that you have many great
qualities within you. Discover those
qualities and strive to become the best
version of yourself. Don't try to be
like me or or whoever else. Be yourself,
but the best version of yourself. All
right, sir. All the best.
Man says, "What is stopping Iran from
making the dirty bomb? because it is
look nuclear weapons are inhuman
the use of nuclear weapons is a crime
against humanity
okay so Iran won't do it at least won't
use it until unless it has no option
left it has no choice left it has
nothing else you know it has no other
options left
dirty bomb is is a very nasty thing a
dirty bomb is a standard chemical explo
explosive with nuclear facile mater
nuclear material added to it. So what a
dirty bomb does is that when it explodes
it spreads nuclear material radioactive
material over a wide area and that
causes cancer and defects and so on so
forth and all that. So that is a it's
terrorism. It's not warfare.
So Iran will probably not use a dirty
bomb unless it has it has been pushed
into a quarter and it has a do right
situation. In that case it may do it
otherwise it won't do it.
Messi aim says how should India balance
energy security trade and diaspora
safety amid the war Iran wars impact on
oil prices and shipping routes. What's
the question? Energy security
trade and diaspora safety.
How do you balance this? You do whatever
you can. That's what you do. You for
figure out balance. Keep everything in
balance. Do whatever you can in all
these departments. So work on energy
security which means you purchase oil
from Russia, purchase from wherever
else. Right? These are different
matters. These are not interconnected.
So you do your best in each department.
Diaspora safety. Well, many of the
diaspora may not even be Indian
citizens. Right. Right. And those who
are Indian citizens, they've chosen to
voluntarily go somewhere. Still, India
will do its best in case there's a
situation to send warships to bring them
back. So these are all different
compartments, different different uh
[sighs]
uh different departments.
MEA fact check has debunked the Indian
port demand. Really? Let's take a look.
Uh what is MEA fact check? MEA fact
check.
MEA fact check.
Let us see.
Ministry of External Affairs official
fact check account.
This doesn't have a great tick mark,
right?
Give me a second. Give me a second. Let
me go to the actual Twitter. This is a
different version.
Okay. So, let us go to Twitter.
All right.
Now if we search for MEA
MEA India
MEA
So we have MEA India. This is an
official government account. How do I
know it? It's got a gray tick mark.
Gray.
It's verified. It's a government or
multilateral organization account. Now,
if I go to MEA fact check, okay, this
account,
it's got a blue check mark. It's just
verified. It's not an official
government account. So, if this
government says it's true or fake, it's
not official government facteing. It is
some private individual who's pretending
to be a government person. Okay? So
don't consider what MEA fact check says
to be official government statements.
Okay? We have to be a little mature in
these matters. If there's a gray check
mark, it's a government account. If it's
a blue check mark, it's a private
person. All right? Please be careful.
Don't be misled and fooled in this
manner.
Okay. Okay. Uh,
hitesh says, "Is India not deporting
illegal Bangladesh, cookies,
infiltrators, etc. due to US EU pressure
since many Indians go there illegally?"
I have no idea. I have no idea. Many
Indians go there illegally. I don't
think many Indians go there illegally.
Some Indians go illegally. Some Indians
will be going illegally. But it's not
like millions of Indians are going
there, right, illegally.
And if Indians are going there
illegally,
well in take action against them, right?
So I don't know why India is not
deporting the millions, tens of millions
of illegal Bangladeshes and the I don't
know how many lakhs of cookies and the
god knows how many Rohingyas and god
knows who else.
I don't know why India is not doing
that. I don't have an answer. Moit but
but thank you very much. So thank you
very much indeed.
R. Rajun Rar Rajger Rahun Rajar says
looking back should we have avoided
Synindor and kept our strength hidden
just did some secret missions looks like
it was a wakeup call for the US.
It was a wakeup call for the US. They
suddenly realized that India is no
longer a pushover.
But whatever pressure the Americans have
applied on us they would have done it
anyway.
They would have done all of this anyway.
So even if we had not done Sindur
by today we would have been in the same
situation where the Americans make
exactly the same demands they're making
of us now. So I don't think if we had
avoided Sindur things would have been
different for us. Yeah.
Okay. Vali Valika Valika says to examine
one's own homeland with clear eyes
unburdened by identity or sentiment.
This is the quiet discipline of a
spiritual mind. You're admirable.
[laughter]
Thank you so much ma'am. Thank you so
much indeed. Thank you.
S Morgan says looks like over reliance
on oil is the case for most of is the
cause for most of these conflicts. Maybe
after this they can accelerate the re
research of viable nuclear fusion
reactors.
There is research that's going on on
nuclear fusion. The Chinese are doing
research. They they have this instrument
uh called a tokamak. Okay. It's a
donut-shaped spheroidal thing and you
have plasma inside and they are doing
pretty good job with that and so on. But
nuclear fusion it's still about 10 20
years away. Okay.
And the nuclear fusion reactor is
massive. You can't use it to power an
airplane or a missile or a car
or a ship. And nuclear fishision which
is standard nuclear reactors they are
huge. And whether it is fusion or
fishision, you need water because
eventually the heat is generated is
driving a steam engine.
>> So nuclear fusion or fishision, it can't
replace oil. That's that's the truth.
Kilki Susan says, "Peace was never an
option." Um, okay sir. Okay.
Mahuya Chak says, "When will the war end
decisively and why is gold not getting
the fuel?" Sir, ma'am, I am not
Nostradamus. I am not one of those
analysts who makes predictions. This is
what is going to happen in the next
three months or whatever and every
prediction comes true always and you
then put it on Twitter. I predicted
this. I am not one of those guys. I I
don't know when the war will end
decisively. I think this war will go on
for months, maybe years. When will it
end? I don't know. Why is gold not
getting the fuel?
Gold not getting the fuel? I'm not sure
what you're asking there, sir. Ma'am, I
don't know.
Why is gold not getting the fuel?
I don't know.
Spade says, "How can we keep society's
morality intact? By teaching the right
values, right principles, and right
behaviors. How do you do it? By
reforming the education system.
The education system is the foundation
of your life. It's everything that goes
into your head during your formative
years. It's what stays with you for the
rest of your life. You have to reform
the education system to do this.
Pril pieces will you debate with pure
economics?
I don't do debates.
You mean economists or economics?
I I generally don't do debates. It's a
waste of time.
Snag says, "I see a Shia ISIS forming in
Iran after this war." All right, sir.
Okay. I hope it doesn't happen, but who
knows? Yeah.
Okay. Ashish says, "Met MEA fact check."
Like I said,
like I said, my friends, MEA fact check
is not an official government account.
Now, you will say, "How do I know?"
I know. I'll tell you how I know.
See
MEA India
this Twitter account has a gray check
mark. It's a government organization
account. Do you understand? It's gray.
Now if you go to MEA fact check
if you go to MEA fact check this account
it's got a blue check mark.
It's got a blue check mark. It is a
private account. It's not a government
account. It is a person, a private
person trying to pretend to be a
government account.
Okay? Do you understand that? Please,
please don't be misled in this manner.
Please don't be fooled. Okay?
Demon Slayer says, "Noam, if Iran loses,
who leads the Shia world?" I suppose
nobody does. The majority of the world's
Shia population is in Iran, by the way.
I suppose no one does or I don't know
who does. I'm not an expert in the
Islamic world or Shia world. So I can't
say really
now. Miss Patel says military muscle
Trump's economic muscle now established.
Yes.
Yeah.
Uh what is that the the thing? Um
power always trumps money.
So military muscle always trumps
economic muscle now established. I've
been saying that for quite some time now
for years actually but now we have seen
it in action.
Yeah I'm glad you saw the pattern M
Patel. All right P Lok thank you very
much sir. Thank you.
So Jani says there appears to be rising
tension pointing towards a possible
conflict.
Is there any indication that India could
enter a warlike situation between April
June? Could it result in territorial
gains? Look, this is a question you
should ask an astrologer.
I don't know what's going to happen
between April and Juel.
I've said that there is high possibility
that in this year there could be an
IndiaPakistan conflict. I've said that.
But when could it happen? I don't know.
Actually, the right time for India is
now. Now. This is the time actually. If
you want to break Pakistan, this is the
time.
Yeah. March 2026. Um yeah
so I think that's this is the right
time.
I don't know if it'll happen between
April or April or June. I can't say
can't say.
Joy Tiwari says is it the perfect time
for India to take over P. Okay. This is
the right time to hit Pakistan if we
have the the the the fortitude to do
that. Yeah we have the military muscle.
We have everything but we have to
consider the effects the second order
third order effects of that what the
[clears throat] US will do how they will
react and so on. But if if you want to
do it now is the right time
really now Miss Patel says are
submarines and missile boats better or
greater than warships? How many do we
need? See, a warship is a large target
and it's visible and it's slow moving
and it's got a lot of people. So, a
warship costs a lot of money, hundreds
of millions of dollars, one warship, a
destroyer.
And it's reasonably easy to destroy. But
a submarine is hidden. It is way harder
to destroy a submarine than to destroy a
warship. A Houthi can destroy a warship.
Submarine takes specialized knowledge to
destroy a submarine to hunt it down to
to discover to find out where it is and
so on. So submarines and submarines are
hidden and they are deadly. They are
deadlier than warships and missile boats
have the advantage that they are cheap
and small and pretty fast. So let's say
you have
$20 million missile boat which carries
three brahos missiles and it can
navigate reasonably fast and if you have
let's say
let's say 10 of those 100 of those
that's just $2 billion
that's like two or three warships but
you've got a 100 missile boats for that
for that money but that gives you the
advantage of quantity
because quantity is a quality of its
own. Have you seen the Iran war? Have
you seen that quantity has a quality of
its own? The Iranian missiles. So yeah,
missile boats in that way are better
than warships, but they have
disadvantages. They don't have long
endurance. They don't have long ranges
and so on. They are good for coastal
defense, but they are a frightening tool
if you use them properly. How many subs
do we need? At least 50. How many
missile boats do we need? Ideally 300.
Pratip Kumar Roy says in a video of
professor Jang he said AI is fake it's
just supervised machine learning gave
examples of edge cases like self-driving
cars he said if someone tries to hit the
car AI can't defend itself what are my
views I haven't thought about it AI is
fake it's it's a software right it's not
we don't know if it's conscious we don't
know if it is actually AGI
it is of course machine learning it can
be supervised can be unsupervised it can
be reinforcement learning it be
whatever.
Um, if someone tries to hit the car, AI
can't defend itself. Yeah, it can't
because we haven't programmed that into
the AI, right? So, I don't know. I
haven't seen the video, so I don't know
exactly what he said, but uh to some
extent he's right. And I'll have to see
exactly what he said to understand the
nuances of what he said.
Sideways says as at what point does
intervention become imperialism? At what
point does intervention become
imperialism? I don't know.
If you have a pattern of intervening
everywhere, that's imperialism. I
suppose if you intervene everywhere and
you push people around and you impose
your will everywhere all the time, if
you have a pattern of doing that
consistently, that's imperialism.
Vidyhimar says, shouldn't Russia, India,
China to Iran's rescue in the national
interest? U
see India is not capable of doing that.
India is not powerful enough. India is a
relatively weak nation and India has a
lot to lose if it gets involved in the
war. So India won't do it. Russia and
China may Russia will definitely do it
if required if required. Not at this
point in time. And China also is kind of
involved in in other ways. Luminance
says are we leaning too much on Israel's
side? I don't know. It it remains to be
seen.
We need to see we need to examine more.
Sonali Sonali says Sonali has become a
new member. Thank you very much ma'am.
Thank you very much and welcome to the
channel's membership.
Pratip Kumar Roy says I used to watch
Peter Zahhan. Too much American bias.
Now this professor Jang from China
sounds smart but I'm confused. Are they
brainwashing us? I don't know. I don't
know. Peter Zahan clearly has a very
clear distinct American bias. He's got
this short videos. I've seen a few of
those. That's a purely American opinion.
Very biased which which is fine. I don't
have nothing against bias. I am biased.
I am biased towards India. So it's fine.
Be biased. So Peter Zahan is is properly
totally biased against towards the US.
Professor Jang I haven't watched. I
watched like one clip of his or
something. U he's from China. Sounds
smart. I'm confused. Well, are the
brainwashing us? I don't know. Jang no.
Zahan definitely is a brainwashing uh
tool of the US. Professor Jang, I'm not
sure. Maybe he is smarter than Zahhan
and maybe maybe more subtle. I don't
know. We'll have to see. I I haven't
seen that. I haven't seen his videos in
detail. So I can't say about Jang.
Zahhan definitely is easy. He can easily
brainwash people.
You know those who are gullible.
H says good evening. How do you see
current geopolitical events infold
unfolding in a few weeks to months over
and over this year end? I think I can at
this point in time let me speak about
the Iran war. I think it will last for
for weeks definitely weeks most likely
several months and possibly even several
years
that's how I see the Iran war otherwise
I don't know
the the other events I can't say
nit says no nothing okay thank you thank
you very much sir ma'am uh pratitar says
global left versus Israel who should we
trust more we should stay out of these
international competitions focus on
ourselves and do Poor thing. That's all
we should do.
Fields strong band says my workout
routine today. Three sets of carefully
monitoring the situation.
Three sets of keen observation. Two sets
of deep concern and five sets of stupid
press release. [laughter]
I love that humor. Love that humor. We
need a bit of humor in life. Always
remember that.
Java bro says, "Benefits or loss of Iran
destroying US bases for us?
um
benefits or loss. If Iran destroys all
the US bases in the Gulf region, we lose
nothing.
We lose nothing. Benefit for us. Well,
we the US may be
may have less leverage over us. Yeah.
So, that's a benefit.
Okay. You pratiba tube. You Pratiba tube
says happy holy and good health sir.
Thank you very much. Thank you very much
indeed. Appreciate your time and
efforts. I think that as a nation with
most volatile ecosystem our sovereignty
is the only leverage way for surviving
any kind of progress and prosperity. If
we lose then what's left? Am I making
sense? Oh you are making a lot of sense.
Of course sovereignty is the most
precious thing we have. The our
sovereignty is the most precious thing
we have
and uh it is under under threat for
sure. The Americans want want to take
away sovereignty for us from us. They
want to turn turn us into convert India
into a vasal state and we have problems
within India internal problems. If we
resolve those internal problems, it will
be harder for the other nations to uh
you know to threaten our sovereignty. So
sovereignty is the most precious thing
that we have. It's the only thing that
allows us to survive long run in the
long run. It's the only thing that
allows us to preserve our civilization.
So we have to maintain our sovereignty,
preserve our sovereignty at any cost. I
completely agree with you. Uh so yeah, I
agree and thank you very much and hopey
happy holy to you and to all the viewers
and good health to you as well and to
all the viewers. Thank you very much.
Bukish says [laughter]
Bukap Pisach hungry ghost. Bukapis says
your views on weapons like white
phosphorus and napal. I think these are
uh war crimes and crimes against
humanity.
[snorts] I like the smell of napal in
the morning. Smells like victory. Robert
Dwal. Okay. Mystic Maz says, "Can I aim
to start a defense company in India?"
Well, you can aim to have it. To start
one, you you'll need the right tools and
you'll need the need the right amount of
money and so on. But you can do it.
There are defense companies in India and
India needs defense companies. But
you've got to be smart in business and
make sure you don't go bankrupt.
Kunal Vashish says, "How will GCC secure
water if Iran can keeps attacking water?
Is impact of GCC pulling out of US
stocks and mass impact of massive AI
bubble globally?
Those are different topics and they okay
impact of GCC. Uh impact how will GCC
secure water if Iran keeps attacking
water? Iran thus far hasn't attacked
water. See these Gulf nations they
depend on desalination plants for water.
What does a desalination plant do? It
takes sea water, distills it and gives
and and and and produces a clean water
[clears throat]
portable drinkable water. That's a
desalination plant. Now if those
desalination plants are destroyed, the
Gulf nations are in a tremendous crisis.
Iran hasn't done that thus far apart
from Fujira. But if that's that's the
weak Achilles heel of the Gulf
countries. If Iran destroys those
desalination plants, game over. I don't
know how what they do about water then.
I don't know. There will be huge crisis.
Uh so yeah, impact of GCC pulling out of
US stocks that will be pretty big
because the GCC nations have invested a
lot of their money petro dollars into
the US stock market. If they pull out,
it's going to crash the stock markets
and massive AI bubble globally. That's a
that that we'll see we'll see remains to
be seen. Dir Kamat says that great tick
account desal has a fact check in his
bio which is an official endorsement.
Okay, let's see that.
Oh,
you may be entirely tremendously right.
so fact check account is me fact check.
So why doesn't this account have a great
tick? What is the government of India
doing? If you don't have a great take,
people will assume it's not a official
account. But uh Rand Juel has put it in
his bio. So it must be an official
account. Okay. So I stand corrected.
Thank you for letting me know sir. I
wasn't uh aware. Thank you so much.
Okay. Fantastic.
Really now Patel says I'd rather take
pain than letting us drag us in war. I
completely agree with you. completely.
Completely.
Mudit
says, "It's 12:00 now. When will you
sleep? What's your normal time?" My
normal time is maybe latest by 11:00.
But when I do these live streams, if
they drag on for longer, I keep it going
cuz I still have about what 18 super
chats left. And uh if people have paid
for this, I better take those questions,
right? All right. H says pure economics
is influencer Kesh of Biddi. Okay. I'm
not aware of this person anyway. Okay.
Uh Ashish Karnak Ashish says me Emac
check is legit. Sar check this bio. I
just did. I just did. So thank you
gentlemen and ladies for pointing it
out. I stand corrected. It is legit but
it looked fake because it is a blue
tick. If the MEA is operating it, why
have they not put a great tick on it?
What are they doing? Seriously,
Christian Sewart says, "Will Razaphi
become king of Iran again? Monarchy? I
hope not. The guy is imminently
unsuitable for being a monarch."
I hope not.
Rajul Lalwani says, "Assume we are a
vasal. How do we put head down and
grow?"
If you are a vasal, a lot of your
destiny and fate is controlled by the
foreigner, by the by the overlord. But
you can still put your head down and
grow. What you can do is you can grow
your economy.
Grow your economy, grow your military as
far as is possible and then find a way
to once again become sovereign. So find
out how exactly your sovereignty is
compromised or diluted
and then when the time comes you rectify
that that situation. That's
theoretically how we do it. But
specifically it will depend on exactly
how the sovereignty is diluted. There
are lots of ways in which sovereignty is
lost. There is territorial sovereignty.
There's for there's there's economic
sovereignty, there's military
sovereignty, there's technological
sovereignty, there are so many different
forms of sovereignty and you may lose
some part of it and then that is what
compromises you. So yeah,
tsunami is Iran attacking Israel
embassies in Middle East. Do you think
India could be next? I don't think we
can write off the probability now that
they hit Turkey. They haven't hit Turkey
as far as I saw. It looks like they have
one missile. It looks like uh it was
aimed at Turkey, but it was intercepted
apparently. So they haven't hit Turkey.
Maybe they tried to hit Turkey. In Iran
is attacking embassies in the Middle
East. Really? Uh where do I find this?
Twitter is the only place I suppose.
Embassies.
Embassies. Really?
Do we have something? Embassies. Latest.
Latest. Come on.
Gulf embassies shut. Embassies.
Embassies. Embassies.
Uh,
embassies.
Okay. I I don't know. Oh, Iran has
threatened to bomb Israel embassies.
It has not done that yet. Okay. So, it's
not done it yet, but it's kind of
threatened to bomb embassies. So, yeah.
Okay. We'll see. I do. You think India
can be next?
Why will India be next? I don't see
India being next in bombing whatever. I
don't see so godliness says India signed
three defense pacts with USA Limo Kasa
Bea. These packs allowed the US to dock
their ships on our ports. Hence they
will park their warships here and create
a safe stock holding. Um I hope not. I
know about the L leaka Kumasa thing
also. Okay.
Yeah, we have signed these things and
see now,
right?
And there's more breaking news.
Uh, what is that? Give me a second.
Sorry.
Breaking news. Apparently,
senior Iranian military official, if the
US and Israel pursue regime change, our
final strike missiles will target the
Demona nuclear reactor and all regional
energy infrastructure.
Well, that's a logical approach. Makes
sense. Uh yeah. Okay. So, I hope the
Americans don't park their warships
here. I hope the government of India
says no, not not allowed. I hope so. We
for biases US has tasted setback. RIC
should take hard and move on.
We should yeah
but I isn't a thing right is embedded in
bricks and ra [snorts] don't get along
together. Especially I and C have an
issue. C has an issue with I. If China
behaves ra can happen but anyway you
mean the three nations should take heart
and move one. I agree with you. I agree.
Shivang brahut. Thank you very much.
Shivang G indeed. Thank you sir.
Sparkestic has become a new member of of
the channel. Thank you very much sir or
ma'am. Thank you very much indeed.
Dave Chandan Malik says what's your
opinion on drone carrier?
You mean an aircraft carrier purpose
built for drones? I think it's an
interesting concept. I've not thought
about it.
Yeah, maybe it's a reasonably decent
idea perhaps. I have not thought about
it. Uh Kosmi re audio says Iran is
almost destroyed. Why are people
delusional? So you are saying I'm
delusional. All right sir.
Madhav says I'm getting payment gateway
not authorized. Message for your course.
Please share the correct website. Thank
you. Uh I'll look into that sir. I'll
look into that. Thank you.
Ratip Kumar Roy says in video titled
psycho history he said it's impossible
to feed any algorithm in self-driving
cars that can protect itself from
getting hit. This is edge case is why
it's fake and can't replace humans.
Okay, that's what professor Jang Jang
said
in a video titled psycho history.
It's impossible to feed algorithm and
self driving cars that can protect
itself from getting hit. That's an edge
case
and it's fake and can't replace human.
Maybe it's an edge case today. As AI
grows and it gets better, maybe it'll
change. I don't know. Yeah.
Vishnu Surendran. Thank you very much.
Vishnu Gav
Yodha says, "How can you say Iran
doesn't target civil when it's proxyed 7
October 7? I mean current Iranians are
not even Persians.
Current
Iranians are not even Persians.
Really? 50% of them are. How do you say
Iran doesn't target civilians when it's
proxy October 7? I not Hamas is not an
Iranian proxy. Hamas is you could say an
ally of Iran because Iran's enemy is
Israel. But Iran did not do October 7.
Iran did not target civilians. Hamas did
that. And Iran is okay with it, I
suppose. But Iran has not done it. The
same way America is okay with Pakistan
targeting India with terrorism, but
America doesn't do it. It's different.
S Morgan says, "I have watched almost
all of Professor Jang's videos. The best
way I can describe him is he is
somewhere between me and Alex Jones."
Alex Jones. Alex Jones is like
that's a very different person.
Okay. So, Professor Jang is bit
somewhere between me and Alex Jones.
Well, okay. That's very interesting. All
right. Thank you for letting me know
between me and Alex Jones. Alex Jones is
I suppose
the polar opposite of me. I suppose I
don't. Okay. Spider-Man says, "My spidey
sense must have missed the live stream
where you explained the dharma issue in
detail." Which dharma issue?
I have done 335 36 live streams. I've
discussed everything in detail. I don't
know which one it was. I can't say. Uh
by the way, how you rate row
capabilities? Is India doing enough? I
don't know how to rate rows capabilities
because I'm not aware of ROW's
operations. Whatever RAW does is it
happens in in the darkness.
I have no idea what operations RAW has
done or is doing. And that's why I have
no context that I can use for rating
RO's capabilities. There are all kinds
of experts who say
how the hell do they know? They are
bluffing. They're fooling you all. I
have zero understanding of RAW. I have
no idea of RO's capabilities. I hope
they are good.
Taran says, "Is Iran a sovereign state?"
Yes, it is. Yes.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Dir Khan says, "Your
opinion on the port fact check posts?"
Uh, you mean MEA fact check?
Give me a second. Uh, I'll go to
Twitter. Uh, MEA fact check, right?
Let's see. Have they said something
about the porta
fact check? Let's see.
Okay. Claims made by made on O US-based
channel that Indian ports are being used
by the US Navy are fake and false. We
caution you against such phase such
baseless and fabricated comments.
Okay. So the Indian government is
stating
that this port thing is this port claim
is fake. Well, I'm so glad. I'm
absolutely tremendously
glad. That's my opinion. I'm pleased.
Very pleased.
Shivang Brahmabat says, "What do you
think about the US calling their
missiles and artilleries back from
Korea? That's the reason why China is
silent."
Um, so the US is considering moving
some THAAD
uh
uh assets from South Korea to the Gulf
region. THAAD is terminal high alitude
area defense. It's a it's a anti-missile
defense system and there's only about 20
30 of those in the world and the
Americans are considering moving though
at least one or two of those from Korea,
South Korea to the Gulf region which
will leave South Korea a little more
exposed to China. I think that is a kind
of a desperate move. I think it is it is
showing you there are holes in the
American
armor right and China is silent for
different reasons. China is not silent
because THAAD is being considered by the
Americans. China is silent because their
whole game of we are superpower. It's
been exposed. They are no superpower.
That's why they are silent. Okay.
Voyager Voyager Thiagi says, "Have you
read the books by George Freriedman?"
Freedman, the storm before the calm and
the next 100 years and how do you do you
agree with the theory that this is
America century? Well, I haven't read
the books by George Freriedman any of
those. So, I don't know.
I can't say let's see what are these
books
okay let's see let us try and google
this
okay George Freriedman the storm before
the calm
let's see
um
the storm before the calm
let's see what Amazon has to say about
this
okay it's got 4.4 four out of five
stars, almost 1,800 reviews. It's a book
from February 2020.
Uh George Friedman,
focus in the US 2020s will bring
dramatic upheaval and reshaping of the
American government, foreign policy,
economics, and culture. Okay, I am not
aware of it. I have not read this book.
So, I can't say what's the other one.
The next 100 years. Let's see
the
next 100 years.
Okay, so here's this obviously is a book
in which it makes predictions. It looks
like a forecast for for the
oh
okay a forecast for the 21st century. So
again it's a for book about forecast
about some kind of forecast that is
making I haven't read these books.
Do I agree with the theory that this is
America century? Um
it can be America century if America
doesn't make blunders. Right now they're
blundering clearly.
So it can be America's century but it
could also end up being Chinese century
or or Russian or Indian century
depending on various factors. So I can't
say as of now whether this will remain
America century. America is obviously
the predominant power in the world
today. No question about that. But look
at the Gulf region. They are unable to
defeat Iran,
right? And they have made a major
miscalculation and blunder here. So if
they continue that sort of behavior, it
will not be remain America century for
too long. So I can't say can't say it
depends if they play their cards right
it will be America's century because
they have the massive advantage of being
the sole superpower. Yeah
s forces are we becoming a US facile
slowly lately Indian geopolitical
decisions have been a bit odd. Uh we are
under tremendous pressure from the US.
It may not be visible in public but we
are under pressure. uh I would not say
as of today that we are already a vasal
but we are under pressure and they are
pushing us trying to push us in that
direction and that's why I've said that
there is a high chance in the next five
years we become a vasal but we are not a
vasal yet so let's be optimistic and
positive
Saikumar
thank you very much sir and Saiikumar
once again thank you very much sir
indeed
um
Kosmir audio says most of the Alex Jones
conspiracies have come to be
>> [laughter]
>> Well,
well,
looks like uh you may be correct about
this. Well, isn't that interesting? The
guy may be whatever. You may not like
his behavior. He may find you may find
him odd or whatever, but looks like he
may he may be right about a lot of
things. So,
Sujay Patak says, "Is Trump doing all of
this purposefully to to bring a
recession?" Trump is doing all of this
to acquire all the oil reserves in the
world to get control of all the oil
reserves. That's why he's doing it.
Okay. KVL
KVL Narima Rao says, "Hi, me and my son
Vishnu are your fans." Thank you very
much, sir. Uh to you as well as your son
Vishnu. Thank you very much both of you.
Thank you very much. Okay. Mustad versus
CIA versus Ro which is the best agency.
How can our robe become
no one agency?
Look, Mossad has the best reputation.
Mossad has the reputation of being the
best agency in the world. Okay, CIA has
been around for a long time and they
have done so many successful operations
around the world. The CIA obviously you
can't take it lightly. Row I have no
idea.
RO is a very secretive organization and
I don't know I don't know how I don't
know how to compare the three when it
comes to Mossad there's lots of books
that have been written by insiders
when it comes to CI again lot has been
written over the over the years raw I
don't know
I hope that RAW is the best agency but
from what I know Mossad is definitely
the best one that is from all the
information in the public in the public
domain how can Rorow become no one
agency what do you mean dual agency.
How can Ro become the best? By by doing
what the best do, I suppose, and then
doing it better.
Kosmir Rodio says, "Are you planning to
write any books?" Yes, I am. I'm in the
process of writing books and they'll
come out and I'll let you all know.
Saiar says, "Is America following Raf
Peter's blood border theory and is Iran
war linked to this theory? What is the
significance of PK in this theory?" I
don't know this theory. It's the first
time I'm hearing this blood border
theory. Let me see what is that
blood border theory.
Blood border theory. Ralph Peter's
proposal in the armed forces journal to
redraw Middle Eastern ah borders along
ethnic
ethnic um
yeah this thing
[sighs and gasps]
okay this one it's a proposal to
redraw the borders of the Middle East
along the ethnic lines ethnic and ethnic
and religious lines
uh is America following this theory
possibly
possibly especially in the term when it
comes to Iran looks like they may be
trying to follow this theory if they
can't do region change they'll do
balconization along those lines what's
the significance of P in theory I'm not
aware I've not studied the theory so I
can't say but America seems to be using
this theory is plan B for Iran possibly
enlightened says why did reconstruction
work in West Germany but not in Iraq
Iraq is a third world country. Nobody is
serious about reconstruction. Germany is
a European nation, white people. So they
will do reconstruction properly. Iraqi
people are not white. They are brown
people. Who cares about brown people?
Why reconstruct Iraq?
Use the reconstruction money for
moneyaundering and whatnot.
Right? That's the problem.
Goullibar says, "What happens if the US
is defeated in the in this war? Why are
they attacking Ecuador?"
You mean the Iran war, right? So
for Iran a victory means survival and
that means defeat for the US. What
happens if if the US is defeated in this
war? Well, there is going to be
political repercussions. Donald Trump
will his political career will be
destroyed. The US uh will lose a
tremendous amount of geopolitical
stature. People will stop respecting the
US. The US may lose some of its ability
to arm twist other nations. Some of its
coercive leverage. a lot of bad things
will happen. Why are they attacking
Ecuador? They are currently bombing
Ecuador, America. They are bombing Iran.
They also bombing Ecuador. Where is
Ecuador? Let's find out.
Ecuador is the small country in
northwest and South America.
Okay, let's let's go to the map.
Ecuador. So, Ecuador is here.
This nation, this is Ecuador. And the
capital city is Ikito or Kito which is
on the equator
and it's south of Colombia and north of
Peru that is Ecuador. And why is America
bombing it? Because they said that there
are some some cartels that are operating
in Ecuador that need to be brought to
heal. Actually what America wants is
that they want an air base in Ecuador
and the Ecuadorian people have voted
against giving it to the US. So the
Americans want de facto position instead
of djour position and that's why they're
attacking Ecuador.
H says interview Alec Jones. Alex Jones
it'll be vibe. [laughter]
Okay let me see maybe I'll do that.
Uh Vatiagi says the Russia Ukraine war
operation Venezuela operation Iran
Israel war have all explo exposed
Chinese defense air systems. Are there
any particular systems that are where
they are truly having an advantage over
America or Russia? I don't know. I am
not a military expert. I'm not somebody
who analyzes military systems, offensive
or defensive systems. I don't know. I
don't know. When it comes to the Iran,
USI Israel war, all
systems are exposed. Not just the
Chinese air defense systems. The
American Patriot system is exposed. The
Israeli iron dope system is also exposed
as you as we can see right so I don't
know about the Chinese systems those are
export versions maybe the Chinese
non-export versions may be better I
don't know is there any particular
system where the Chinese have genuine
advantage over America or Russia I don't
know I don't sorry
Bargav says most untampered rigid gita
or something else I don't know I don't
know sir
hopefully the rigid but I can't Today
Ankita Kachab Ankita G evening I missed
the earlier part of the stream. My
question India is taking side India
taking side of the US is very
disappointing. Keeping in view that US
has a history of betraying and harming
its own allies. How is this going to
impact India? Thank you sir. Already
answered. Did I already answer this? Uh
let me anyway answer it. See yeah US
India taking the US side is
disappointing
but India has taken the American side
verbally not through actions. India is
not supporting America's war on Iran.
India is not doing anything that
actually harms Iran. India has verbally
kind of been on the American and Israeli
side. Right? And we know that the US has
a history of betraying and harming its
own allies. That like what we are seeing
right now in the Gulf, the US was
supposed to defend its Gulf allies but
they are being exposed to the missiles
and the Americans are not defending
them.
So uh that's the thing and the
government of India has decided to do
this out of practical reasons not
ideological reasons so that we will face
the least amount of harm from the US.
How will it impact India? Hopefully not
too badly. Hopefully it doesn't have any
real impact on India. Hopefully. So the
impact is that we don't get dragged into
the war. The impact is that Iran can
also see that we are only verbally on
the side of the US and Israel. We not
doing anything actually that harms Iran.
So hopefully that is what the world
sees.
Cosmir Rod says Trump will split split
Iran, Kurdistan, Persia, etc. Okay sir,
that's your prediction. Thank you.
Goullibar says 200 US service members
have filed formal complaints alleging
that military commanders are framing the
current war with Iran and as a biblical
ar biblical Armageddon.
Seems boots on ground morale is down.
Yeah, I'm not surprised that there have
been complaints. 200 US service members
have complained. Okay. Biblical
Armageddon. Biblical Armageddon.
I'm not sure if the morale is down or
not. I heard stories of Boral not being
great in aircraft carriers and so on,
but can't say.
But yeah. Okay.
Uh Ritik Yedwani says might sound like
immoral or ethical question right now
but most people make their money during
the war times. What can one do to make
some money? I don't know how to make
money during war times. So I am the
wrong person to ask this question and
yes people make money during times of
crisis for sure but I am not an expert
in that so I can't say.
Pushina is a new member. Thank you very
much sir. Thank you very much. Welcome
to the membership of the channel.
H says it's a pleasure to see you smile
and laugh sir. Thank you. Yes, I I
should do a little more of that,
shouldn't I? Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Gotham says, "Mayoc clinic versus AIMS.
How do I compare?" I haven't been in
either and I hope I am never in either,
so I don't know, but I suppose Mayo
Clinic would be better. I suppose
I
says, "Israel using Indian
military-industrial complex for their
weapons development. Seems what US MIC
was doing in world war I like it as no
morality in war earn money US way is
Israel using the Indian military
industrial complex for weapons
development. I think there are joint
ventures between India and Israel. We
have jointly developed multiple uh
weapon systems like the barak system
which is frighteningly good and so on.
So I think it's as long as it's mut
mutually beneficial for both countries
well and good. I'm happy with it.
Okay. Hey, the posture code says did
Iran do a nuclear test earthquake
observed when? Just now or some time
ago? Sometime ago the earthquake that
happened it happened at a depth of 10 km
which means it's natural. It's not
man-made. If there's a new one, well,
we'll see. We'll have to see about that.
Golibbar says the US has lost three to
four fighter jets in a war with a
non-uclear state. No one is crying that
the US has lost these fighter jets.
India operation synindur people were
like India has lost the war. Why?
Because Indians don't know how to think.
Indians think that a war is like a
football match where there's a score of
7032 or whatever. During their the
American invasion of Iraq in 2003, the
Americans lost more than 50 planes. Did
anybody cry that America has lost the
war? No. Indians don't know how to
think. Indians are immature and that's
why we have the situation. The Americans
have already lost at least three fighter
planes and we can see those planes being
shot down. But no one is crying that the
US has lost the war. So yeah, Indians
need to
grow a bit of maturity.
All right, that brings me to the end of
today's live stream. All the questions
are dealt with. Thank you very much
everybody for the questions. It was very
interesting. There are a lot of
questions and there's a lot a lot
happening. So I'll end this live stream
over here this point in time. I will do
the next one very soon probably
in a day or in a couple of days maybe
maybe Friday or Saturday. Until then
take care. I think Sunday there's a
World Cup final so I suppose I can do it
there but yeah I'll do it very soon.
Until then take care. Uh Pratip Kumar
good night sir. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. Injured soccer
player. Thank you very much. Appreciate
that. And let's end the live stream with
that. Thank you very much everybody.
Good night. Good day. And I look forward
to seeing you very soon. Keep asking
questions. Keep raising your standards.
I'll see you very soon. Good night. Good
day. Bye-bye.